I'm sorry for shoving others aside and volunteering to come with you.
Don't worry. Flatt and Svin are on extracurricular lessons anyway.
Make sure to be very careful while you're on the train.
Is it a dangerous train?
Rail Zeppelin.
It's a train that superhuman vampires created
to make deals with Mystic Eyes.
Its existence itself is equal to that of the underworld.
It's possible that one of those customers is the culprit who stole the relic.
Even if they aren't,
only supernatural beings would board this train.
So that's why you brought glasses that eradicate Mystic Eyes.
You really make good preparations.
Adashino Hishiri!
You again?
I expected you to be on the move based on the materials concerning Wills.
I was thinking some Lord was here,
but I didn't expect the rumored Modern Magecraft Theory.
It has been a while, Lady.
Even the figurehead of Norwich recognizes my face at the least?
It's Olga-Marie.
Olga-Marie Arsimilat Animusphere.
She's the daughter of the Lord of Astromancy.
So, do you have some particular Mystic Eyes you're after?
We'll see about that, won't we?
I'll make this clear,
but Astromancy will make sure to win this year's auction.
Even if I'm up against a Lord, I'm not going to go easy.
It seems you overestimate me.
My lady, it's almost time.
All right, Trisha.
In any case, I ask you one thing. Don't get in the way of Animusphere!
So scary, so scary.
My lady.
It's unusual for an Animusphere to descend from the mountains.
It's natural for Astromancy to show interest in Mystic Eyes that can predict the Mystics.
Let's go.
Somehow,
this place is larger than it looks.
I told you, didn't I?
This train itself...
is the underworld.
But they sure are all notable figures.
I know the faces of half of them,
but they're all monsters.
No way!
Karabo Frampton...
from the Holy Church.
Impossible! The Holy Church came out here?
The one that contends against the Clock Tower?
Stop it. I don't mean to stir up any trouble here.
I'm going to participate in the auction, as well.
Do you object?
Pardon me.
No, that reaction was to be expected.
No way! Professor El-Melloi II is here, too?
Welcome aboard!
It's you...
Yvette! Why are you here?
My family is an authority of Mystic Eyes!
We're regulars of the auction on the Mystic Eyes Collection Train! It's for sure!
Oh, but I didn't expect Caules to be here, too.
Are you one of his sycophants?
No, though it's true that I asked him to be here.
Professor, it's not good to be cheating!
Oh no, maybe BL can be a thing?
I'm sorry if I'm not good with multiplay!
How cute.
You want to be his mistress?
Yes! I'm a regular at sneaking into the bedroom!
All right, you stay quiet.
If possible, jump out of that window right this second.
Pardon the interruption of your pleasant chat.
I'm Leandra, and I'll be the auctioneer for this train.
And I'm Rodin, the conductor.
And now, Rail Zeppelin will be departing as scheduled.
The auction in three days' time
will have many prized Mystic Eyes
from our collection.
Please make sure to spend your time here with no regrets.
But...
the one who invited me never showed up.
Shall we go look for him?
Stop it. Something will surely happen now that I've been lured out.
There's no good in simply worrying under our current conditions.
Master?
Let me sleep.
I was up all night last night, too.
This must be it.
Welcome, Shishigou Kairi.
I didn't think I'd be called over to a fancy place like this.
Though, I can't imagine that it would suit your palette, Lady Reines.
This is a place my elder brother patronizes.
Besides, they serve delicious sandwiches.
So,
what does the little sister of a Lord want with a freelance magician like me?
My brother's catalyst for the Holy Grail War has been stolen.
You can't mean the ritual utensil to summon a Heroic Spirit!
What was stolen is the mantle of Iskandar, King of Conquerors.
That's quite an item to bring out.
Yes. It was something that Kayneth specially obtained.
The mantle of the King of Conquerors...
could create a magical bond with Iskandar or one of his subordinates.
That's something any Necromancer would like to get his hands on.
My elder brother has boarded the Mystic Eyes
Collection Train in order to get it back.
Come on, you can't be telling me to go back him up there!
No. Apparently, it's absolutely impossible to board that train without an invitation.
What I need are clues about the perpetrator.
I see. So, playing detective...
We're talking about investigating a perpetrator who can steal a catalyst from a Lord's vault.
I need someone who can deal with things getting a bit rough.
I see what you're getting at.
But why aren't you resolving this within Modern Magecraft Theory?
Of course, it's because I suspect someone on the inside the most.
Isn't that how it goes?
Indeed.
Oh, and I'll give you an assistant.
A reliable one.
Oh, little apprentice! Over here!
Will you take this plate?
Why don't you order something?
Oh no. I'm not feeling too well.
Oh, I see.
What about Professor?
Oh, not yet.
I'm sure it's something like him asking for five more minutes
because he's not a good riser, right?
Five more minutes.
You really know a lot.
Of course, I want to be his mistress.
"A mistress," you say?
You're not fazed by this comment.
I guess you're not a rival, then.
The Mystic Eyes of Viewing Emotions.
My family's magecraft cuts gems and turns them into Mystic Eyes.
This one can see human emotions.
I'm sorry.
What comment should I have been fazed by?
I see.
This isn't worth my time.
Welcome, Professor!
Yvette...
Now, now, come on over!
Your cute apprentice is here, too!
How was it?
I asked the conductor about who sent us the invitation.
He said it was one of the free slot invitations that are handed out to several people.
They don't know who originally had this invitation, either.
I see.
Quite a few free slot invites are sent out.
Is that so?
If they don't invite new people, the auction becomes too routine.
There should be over a dozen of those sent out every year.
So, we won't be able to trace them through the invitation.
That's impossible.
More like you could've asked me instead of Caules
if it was something about this train!
Why I didn't do so will be the topic for your self-study!
That's so cruel! You're so mean, Professor!
Now, please bait them out well,
Great Detective.
Professor!
This was wedged into the door.
Oh.
This is...
"I am honored that you noticed the invitation
and made your way out here."
Master...
Yeah, it's from that thief.
They want me to head to the cargo bay at twilight.
Lord El-Melloi II?
Do you mind if I speak with you for a short while?
I don't know if I can speak of anything that would win your favor.
I can't quite say that I'm a customer for this auction.
I feel you're the most suited person in the Clock Tower to talk about this with.
I mean, it's about the Holy Grail War.
I'm listening.
What does Astromancy want to do with the Holy Grail War?
How the previous El-Melloi passed away
was discussed over at Animusphere, as well.
Besides, it's so talked about that you hear of it even if you're a shut-in.
How you want to join the Holy Grail War even by mobilizing the Sophia-Ri family.
I didn't think Animusphere would be that interested in the ordinary world.
This is a fragment of a planet, too.
Looking at the heavens and looking at Earth are the same thing.
Observing the planet.
We concluded that you came here to purchase Mystic Eyes
as a weapon to use in the Holy Grail War.
Are we mistaken?
That's not exactly correct, I guess you could say.
What I want is the eye-catcher of this auction, Rainbow Mystic Eyes.
Rainbow Mystic Eyes?
The ultimate operation of celestial bodies within the human body!
I'm not well-versed, but is it something that amazing?
Each Mystic Eyes has a rank.
Higher caliber Mystic Eyes are ranked as "Gold-class," then "Jewel-class,"
and "Rainbow-class" is a rank above those.
I didn't think it actually existed.
I believe almost no one at the Clock Tower
has seen Rainbow Mystic Eyes.
But if such Mystic Eyes are going to be put up for auction,
wouldn't you think that I'd purchase it for the Holy Grail War?
I don't think El-Melloi in its current state has that much financial prowess.
You sure are blunt about it.
I see. So, you're certain there'll be Rainbow Mystic Eyes at the auction.
It's fine, Trisha.
The talk will go smoother if we show at least that card to them.
Understood.
It's because...
I had a vision.
Oh, this is perfect.
Lord El-Melloi II,
can you raise your right hand?
Like this?
Yes.
Three, two...
one.
I'm sorry! I need to head outside!
The Mystic Eyes of Premonition, huh?
I had a vision where Rainbow Mystic Eyes were put up for auction.
I'm sorry! Please excuse me!
So, what do you want me to do?
When the Rainbow Mystic Eyes come out,
I want you to bid if some other fool were to bid for them.
Oh? You were the one who told me I don't have the fortune to do that.
No magus would be foolish enough to antagonize two families of Lords, right?
If you can fold as soon as the others do,
I can curb the damage to a minimum.
For now, I'll comply with your request.
Thank you.
It helps me out that you can have constructive conversations.
I'll give you a suitable reward if you assist me.
Are you all right, miss?
I'm sorry.
It seems I'm slightly motion sick.
After all, this train doesn't run along typical railroad tracks.
The Mystic Eyes Collection Train runs along magical tracks built atop leylines.
If you're not used to it, your condition will worsen.
Get some sugar and hydrate yourself.
That should make things slightly better.
Thank you very much.
A-Are you okay?
I had no intent of looking.
I see. So, you're not a magus.
The guise of King Arthur...
Such a thing...
How do you know that?
I'm sorry.
I can see the past with my Mystic Eyes.
There's no need to see such things, either.
Thank you. I'm fine now.
As you said, I'm not a magus.
I call myself "Master's Apprentice," but that's only in name.
That's why you're unsure of whether or not you're of any use to the Lord.
Yes.
You're fine. You're already someone he finds necessary.
I'll guarantee it.
Is that magecraft, as well?
No.
It's what you call "life experience."
May I sit next to you?
You have something else?
When we did our research about the previous Holy Grail War,
we got to know about a boy named Waver Velvet.
My oh my.
Wasn't that a terrible record to see?
He was only a third-generation magus.
He was far from what you could call promising,
but he returned alive from the Holy Grail War.
However, upon return,
he was resolved to do something
and succeeded the El-Melloi family,
now being called a "Lord."
Only in name.
That must mean the Holy Grail War was a large turning point in his life.
For instance,
meeting a hero of yore.
An interesting speculation.
Yes,
one more to add to speculation.
If you were to summon the same Heroic Spirit once again,
wouldn't the Servant have no memories
of racing through this world with you?
I'm surprised that Astromancy was interested in things as such.
That definitely is something that has nothing to do with the stars.
They say that connections are similar to stars, you know.
There's something I'd like to ask myself.
What kind of Rainbow Mystic Eyes did you folks have a vision of?
I believe we have no need to tell you that much in detail.
No matter which Mystic Eyes Collection Train you're on,
I cannot imagine them being able to ready two sets of Rainbow-class Mystic Eyes at once.
I see, that is reasonable.
Humans live being dependent on information,
and they die being bound by information.
Of which, vision provides the largest amount of information.
Vision is the first magecraft in human history.
To incorporate information can be said as the foundation of magecraft.
That is why humans are dominated by memories, by information.
To have Mystic Eyes is to accept the destiny of being bound by them.
If you are going to purchase Mystic Eyes,
please take that into careful consideration.
I'm greatly obliged by your advice.
This train will stop at this location for about two hours.
You are free to spend this time either aboard the train or wandering outside...
Master...
Have you heard something about myself and the Holy Grail War?
No.
No, but such a...
Servants don't have memories of previous summons, huh?
That was something I've understood for the longest time.
But Master, if there is someone you are devoted to,
wanting that person to have memories of you is only natural, isn't it?
Right. It's not like I don't care whether or not he has forgotten me.
However, there's someone I want to meet despite all that.
There is something I want to confirm.
There is something to settle and finish
so I can walk past the last ten years.
Yes, I'm fixated on just that, something so petty.
Each of us being remembered
and being able to relish each other's memories.
Such happiness is too big a reward even if it was deferred.
I can't possibly pay that off in my life.
Master...
Gray!
Yes!
This is...
I was just getting a breath of forest air.
And...
when I returned,
Trisha...
Trisha was...