Professor, what do you mean by that?
Just what it looks like.
You're the true culprit.
You controlled Father Karabo to murder Trisha Fellows.
That can't be, Master!
I don't think you have neither a motive nor evidence.
Yeah. That's why I was waiting for him.
I was having a really hard time, Professor.
If Svin hadn't been able to find me,
I don't know what would've happened.
Mr. Caules?
You've really done it this time, Waver!
What in the world is going on here?
This is what it means.
Miss Reines!
It was really strenuous to fly here using Touko Travel.
Well, Flatt's end went through the worst of it, for sure.
That sure was an exciting extracurricular lesson!
Oh boy! To predetermine a destination,
then force a flight spell as if pulling a super-lengthy piece of rubber...
I didn't think you could implement flight by magecraft in that fashion.
Looked like they were going at least Mach 1.
I wonder if they're still alive.
They can definitely arrive at the Rail Zeppelin
without an invitation that way.
It's so logical that the means and the end were completely reversed!
It's an ingenious trick!
I will never do anything like that!
When did you realize it?
I thought I had perfectly traced the real Caules.
You only made one mistake.
That was treating me.
It would be impossible for Caules to perform such a splendid treatment.
I see. I overdid it because I'd be troubled if you passed away.
So, you had already swapped by the time we boarded the train.
My preparations were perfect.
You didn't feel any doubt, did you?
And the source of all that information was you,
wasn't it?
He promised me that I could analyze the Mystic Eyes once we won the auction!
So, that's why I asked Miss Adashino
to put up an act for us.
I see.
So, everything was buying time just for this.
Who are you?
Don't you have an idea who already?
Yes. It's a pleasure to meet you,
the previous department head of Modern Magecraft Theory...
Doctor Heartless!
Doctor Heartless. The man whose heart was stolen by Fairies.
Only you can easily open the safe of Modern Magecraft Theory
and also provide funding to Yvette.
That's right.
I've been wanting to meet you.
That can't possibly be all.
Oh?
That transformation spell is similar to the spell style of Gurdoa Davenant.
The sponsor for Sir Davenant provided funding for the Marbury Workshop,
and was trying to do something
using the power of leylines.
You've been leaving a trail all along
as if you were an examiner watching over poor-performing students.
I see. But don't you have more deductions, as well?
That's right. What happened to the whydunit?
This case is nothing but a residual image. It has long since attained its objective.
So, it wasn't meant to obtain Miss Trisha's Mystic Eyes?
The main objective lies elsewhere.
The Holy Grail War.
Heartless seeks the Holy Grail War?
I have to hand it to Luvia. She did good research.
To think that you,
who supposedly went missing, were jointly investigating with Lord Animusphere...
So, this man was who my father requested the investigation?
You secretly joined forces with Astromancy seven years ago,
and controlled Karabo to execute a serial murder.
And taking their Mystic Eyes, head and all while still alive,
you used their powers to obtain, monopolize and hide information about the Holy Grail War.
Good. Very good.
But those are only circumstantial evidence and speculation.
You have nothing concrete.
The Greater Grail can't become a wish granter.
That fact despaired Lord Animusphere.
However, that doesn't mean that the Greater Grail is worthless.
What do you mean?
Heroic Spirits, my lady. The fact that you can summon Heroic Spirits...
There's no falsehood within that function.
Heartless, you created a Holy Grail.
Excellent!
The Mystic Eyes Collection Train
and the Child of Ainnash.
By placing both of them on the same leyline, you are sure to create a distortion.
The birth of another Holy Grail.
I see. So, you could call it a variant of the Holy Grail.
Of course, this alone can't materialize as that of the Holy Grail War.
You need some trick, such as connecting this leyline to Japan.
But he needed something more than anything else to pretend it was a Greater Grail.
He needed a man who was once a Master,
Waver Velvet.
A previous Master and a Holy Grail variant linked to the Greater Grail...
That's the stage contraption you needed.
In other words, your crime of summoning a Servant has long since been committed. Right?
The Holy Grail War was truly intriguing.
Because it was an impossible fairy tale even for magi,
I was enchanted by it more than anything else.
Trisha's murder was nothing more than an addendum.
Deleting the Mystic Eyes of Premonition that has the possibility of reaching your true guise,
and obtaining it if possible...
Along with Sir Karabo's Mystic Eyes.
However, she predicted the murder and hid her own head.
Her determination has guided me all the way here.
How touching!
I understand the situation.
Were you the one who summoned the Child of Ainnash and attacked this train?
I guess that's how things went.
If it is determined that you attacked this train,
you will lose your right to partake in the auction.
Oh, brother. So, things did end up this way. But...
this is not enough.
Adashino!
I order you with my Command Spell!
Come hither!
Adashino!
You finally called for me, Master.
The Lord had such an interesting tale. I couldn't help but overstay.
What is that?
That is a Heroic Spirit!
I'd been thinking about what exactly you were.
I've introduced myself as Hephaestion.
It's a matter of what class,
such as why you didn't disclose your class despite disclosing your True Name.
The Holy Grail is a fake, the Master is a fake, the Command Spells are fake!
Normally, such a nonsensical spell wouldn't succeed.
In other words, she is...
Yes. Her class is something along the lines of a fake Heroic Spirit.
Exactly. I've named this new class "Faker."
Then, who are you saying I am?
The shadow double for Iskandar.
Isn't that so?
Hold on, elder brother! That of all things is too unreasonable!
Oh? By that, you mean...
From the tales elder brother has told me,
the King of Conquerors was a redheaded giant over two meters tall!
That's right. However,
said king originally in legend supposedly had a small frame with black hair,
and heterochromia with one eye embracing shadows of the night
and the other embracing the blue skies.
Faker is a residual image of the king,
a magical double who protected the king
by fabricating gender, appearance and his entire existence!
You are correct, magus.
And I have no intent of listening to any more of your nonsense.
I wouldn't mind fighting right here.
But many Mystic Eyes will be sacrificed by doing so.
Could you possibly open up the Pandemonium for us?
Understood.
Yvette, what do you plan on doing?
I'll honestly accept my sentence.
I don't want to spend my life as a fugitive.
Oh, I have been rejected. Well then...
You're not getting away!
Oh brother... I do feel it would be wise for us to part ways here.
You haven't returned the relic to me!
Oh, I see!
Here.
Well then...
Hold on!
Faker, there's something I want to ask you, too.
I said I had no intent of listening to your nonsense!
I'm guessing you have no name at all
in order to act as a magical double.
Yes, that's right.
I have no name.
I was born as the twin sister for Hephaestion,
and sacrificed to the gods.
If you have no name, you can absorb all curses targeting Iskandar.
A powerful adaptation of the concept of correspondence.
That king had tried many a time to give me a name,
and I vehemently declined each time.
That's all. That's all there is to it, magus.
Then, one problem still remains.
The reason why you didn't appear as part of Ionioi Hetairoi!
Shut up!
Add!
Sorry about that, Gray!
Master, please strike her with everything you want to say to her!
Damn you!
Faker, I believe I ordered a retreat.
That comes after I lop his head off!
A spell?
Add, devour it!
This is great magical power!
What a nuisance!
You said how the king had tried to give you a name?
If so, he didn't accept your circumstances!
There was no way he'd allow you to be treated as a thing with no name!
And the reason why you weren't part of Iskandar's army...
was because you yourself harbor hatred toward his army!
You bastard!
You won't move that tongue of yours anymore!
Crafted Tree! I made it in time!
A child's play of a spell!
Caules!
Miss Gray, take care of the rest!
Okay!
Doctor Heartless!
Unraveling Faker's mystery was amusing.
How kind of you.
Dismantling, Lord El-Melloi II...
You can't help but to dismantle anything and everything relating to the Mystics.
I will do so to your experiments, too, right now.
I see. Then, I guess I should try to resist.
Overturn thyself...
my heart.
That's...
Yes.
I've unleashed the Child of Ainnash!
Does it intend on devouring this entire train?
The curtain will now fall on your clown act!
Master!
He mentioned it was pretty rough when he realized that the Earth was round,
and there was no Sea at the End of the World.
I guess king and subject are rather alike.
The empire seeking Okeanos crumbled, and everything we dreamed of was lost.
Where else do you see such a horrible outcome?
What's so funny?
No. I just thought it was very much like him.
In one way or another, he always misses something at the end.
Maybe he actually is not talented at all.
Master...
Thank you.
What did you say?
There wasn't a day in the past ten years where I felt vexed by all this.
Even if I were to follow in his footsteps, I didn't know what I needed to be doing!
But if I were to tell him I was able to retaliate against his other self,
I'm sure he'd roll around, getting a good laugh.
You believe you can win against me?
Gray, will you assist me?
Yes! I'm going in!
Forgive me, Master!
I was planning on being loyal to my allegiance, but...
Not much I can do about this.
A magnificent provocation,
to be expected of someone who experienced the Holy Grail War.
It's rare for a Servant and a Master's volitions to coincide.
I'm sorry, but I'll have her riveted down!
You think you can stop me?
No, that is my job!
Karabo Frampton?
But you are blind.
They were given back to me
as the auction has been annulled!
Mr. Karabo?
You dotard!
This is...
As long as the fact that there was a slash rises up from the past,
once you enter its range, nothing astral or physical can defend against it!
You will suffer for controlling me, Heartless!
Oh?
However, what will you do with this many branches?
There's nothing we can do...
if we were by ourselves.
The shape of stars.
The shape of space.
The shape of God.
Right. That's right!
The shape of self.
I finally understand!
Celestial bodies are hollow.
I should be angry. It's all right for me to be occasionally angry.
Hollowness is empty space.
God resides within empty space.
Were you waiting for me to be angry someday, Trisha?
Stars.
Cosmos.
Gods.
Animus.
Antrum.
Unversed.
Anima, Animusphere!
Miss Olga Marie's spell?
Just like what I arranged.
This is a surprise.
Did you predict this, as well?
It's an elementary deduction.
A good time for the second arrow!
Completed loading the Mystic Eyes.
Commencing sequence for Great Projection of Mystic Eyes.
Anchor Car Rilcabellow has completed connection with the Mystic Eyes!
Analysis complete in 3... 2... 1.
Complete.
Deploying Spiritual Revolving Lens Rose-Eye!
Great Projection of Mystic Eyes!
How horrible.
What a wet blanket of an ending.
We're going home, Faker.
No!
Not yet!
I won't let you!
You saw it.
I'll start with you first!
So, you were waiting for this opportunity
when I'd be reliant on my Mystic Eyes?
Yes.
Though, without Father Karabo,
I don't think the spell would've made it in time.
"Glory lies beyond the horizon.
Challenge it because you know it to be unattainable.
Speak of conquest and make it real.
For my men who watch behind me."
That's what he said.
You're merely an underling who fawned on him for half a month!
You have no right to speak of our fallen king!
O shadow of the king,
even if you were eradicated from history,
your meaning is never lost!
That's why...
I'm standing right here!
If so, try surviving from hereon, as well!
Jeez.
Gray...
I'm leaving this to you.
Master?
That was...
everything I had.
I entrust you with my life.
My loyalty is with my king!
This one moment, allow me to borrow the name of thunder!
Gray.
Rave.
Crave.
Deprave.
Grave...
...me.
That lance is filled with prayer.
A prayer consolidated into thirteen shapes.
Listen attentively to the voices of the lance.
To the ways that in ancient times, someone prayed.
He said "ways"! Hey, Gray! You've had your head hung down,
knees cradled in a corner of a room for all this time!
But you know, it's time for you to ask!
What you yourself want to do!
Nobody will know if you don't tell them!
I want to...
protect Master and everyone else!
I want to be someone who can protect!
Indeed, I heard it, Slowpoke Gray!
Pseudo-Personality suspended.
Mana yield exceeds regulation.
Second stage restraint rescinded.
Seal Thirteen... Decision, start!
This is a battle that will harm no Elemental.
Approved.
This is a battle against an enemy mightier than oneself.
This is a battle to live.
Approved.
This is a battle that does not stand against humanity.
This is a battle for truth.
Approved.
Third stage restraint rescinded.
Grave for you.
Old Mystics.
Exterminate sweet mysteries!
All will return to the void!
Now, race forth... Hecatic Wheel!
Sacred lance,
removing restraints!
Rhongomyniad!
The Lance that Shines to the End of the World