You remember Mary Lil Fargo, don't you, dear brother?
She's the only daughter of the Fargos, a branch family of the Animuspheres
which heads the Astromancy Department. As well as a former student of mine.
Why bring her up?
The Animuspheres sent a messenger over the other day.
It seems Mary's father,
Ernest Fargo, passed away suddenly—
his corpse found dismembered in his own home, no less.
All the other magi who went to try and make sense of it ended up throwing in the towel.
So they're hoping the Lord of Modern Magecraft Theory might be able to share his insight.
I have one question.
Why should I involve myself
in this case to begin with?
Oh, that's quite simple.
Aside from you, dear brother,
all the first-rate magi are exceedingly wealthy.
Mary's soon to have a sizable inheritance fall into her lap, no doubt.
If you resolve this neatly,
you can expect a generous reward.
And I'm sure that would go quite a ways
towards repaying those debts of yours.
What a bloody pain.
Come now, dear brother.
Can't you muster the faintest enthusiasm
for the chance to avenge your dear student's father?
I don't fancy myself a champion of justice,
nor have I any intention of becoming one now.
Gray.
Can I leave this to you?
Yes, sir.
A rotunda, eh?
Begging your pardon, Master?
See that section of the building with the domed roof?
The roof represents the sky,
so then the interior is the earth below it.
In other words, this house is
its own self-contained world.
The master of the house is
the god of that world, after all.
The god of that world?
How could none of the others figure it out
with clues this obvious staring them in the face?
Master?
No matter.
Let's get started.
I am Claire, a maid in the employ of this residence.
Lord El-Melloi has arrived, Mistress.
Oh, Professor!
I'm so happy you're here!
I really didn't know what I would do!
This isn't the time to wallow in misery.
Remember what I taught you?
A magus must always keep a cool head,
especially in times of crisis.
You're right, Professor.
Who's this with you?
Gray, my apprentice.
You'll have to forgive her
for keeping her face shrouded.
Now then, please share with me the details of the incident.
Allow me to supply those.
And you are?
It is an honor to meet you, Lord El-Melloi.
My name is Fernando Li,
Ernest's longtime friend and fellow researcher.
Spiritual evocation is my stock in trade.
Oh? As a spiritual evocationist, shouldn't you have been able to question the spirit of the victim himself?
That was the first thing I tried,
expecting it would fail,
and it did. There's a bounded field
surrounding the whole estate, it seems.
Better not trust anything this geezer tells you.
Alec!
He's probably the one who killed Uncle Ernest and all, see.
Alec! How could you say such a
terrible thing to Mister Fernando?
You're Mr. Fargo's nephew Alec, I take it?
Ooh, ain't this a feather in my cap!
To think a fellow like you has heard of a dropout magus like me!
Are you saying you suspect me?
There's no honor among magi.
Researcher chums or not, you'd slit each other's throats in the night to get ahead. Ain't that right?
I'm afraid I must agree.
But what about you? You did owe an enormous sum of money to Ernest, did you not?
Yes.
On the day of the incident, Master Alec
got into a heated argument with
the master about that very thing.
Claire, you mouthy little—
Alec! Stop that right now!
I don't want to hear any more from you either, Claire.
Know your place and keep out of our discussion.
I'm terribly sorry, Mistress.
Were you present in the mansion
on the night of Ernest Fargo's death?
Yes, sir, of course.
The only people here that night were the four of us, myself included.
I see.
Now then, I'd like to see the place where Ernest Fargo died.
According to the report I received, Sir Fargo's body was dismembered
and left lying in seven places within the mansion,
five of them in the hall here.
The structure of this hallway makes it well-suited to magecraft involving celestial bodies.
The seven greater planets, is it?
The seven greater planets?
Now that I think on it, you did teach us in class how the planets correspond
to seven parts of the human body.
Correct.
If we examine how the body was arranged,
it should become eminently clear what kind of magus did this, and what magecraft they were planning.
Is this all an oh-so-exalted Lord is good for?
Any magus would know that,
even one still clinging to its mother's teat.
Were the matter so simply solved, we'd never have gone to the trouble of calling for you.
We've preserved the crime scene with our own magecraft.
Let me have a look.
My word.
Now do you get it, Lord?
Indeed.
I can see why you found this so mystifying.
Don't forget our family is a branch of the Animuspheres.
Astromancy is our bread and butter.
Do you think your rudimentary ideas
weren't already the first things we tried?
The arrangement of the body doesn't match the tenets of any traditional craft we know.
It's a thoroughly modern form of magecraft.
So you thought that the head of Modern
Magecraft Theory might have an inkling?
Correct.
I'll offer you what meager help I can.
Please do so, Professor.
It feels hard to breathe inside this house.
It's so much like a cage.
Aptly put, Lady. "Cage" is the perfect word for it.
Master, might it be that Sir Fargo's killer is among the four?
This mansion was enclosed by a powerful bounded field on the day of the incident.
I can scarcely imagine an outsider breaching it.
Mr. Fernando would have had his eye on
Sir Fargo's research, and Mr. Alec his wealth.
Each seems to have a motive.
And then there's the one who stood to inherit both the money and the magecraft when he died: Mary.
Dear me, Master! You suspect Mary as well?
We're only speaking of possible motives here, Lady.
So the suspects we must consider number three.
No, there's still one more.
You don't mean Claire, the maid?
But she's no magus.
Dismemberments like this happen all over the world.
The killer needn't be a magus.
This is only supposition, but I'd wager Miss Claire was being physically abused by her employer.
Abused...
Her hesitant movements and the way
she shrunk back from others
were telltale signs of someone with
bodily injuries underneath their clothing,
worn long to hide the marks of that very abuse.
How horrid.
If Miss Mary knew of it—
I'm sure she was well aware.
But that doesn't mean she could stop it.
Why not?
Magi treat their own children as property.
She wouldn't have dared defy her father.
Any magus household is liable to have skeletons
of a similarly gruesome nature in its closets.
Mary is as much a suspect as the rest.
Then all four of them have a motive.
Exactly.
Magi by nature are those who can control unbelievable supernatural phenomenae.
Therefore, the howdunit—
the means by which the crime was committed—
can only be guessed at.
But the whydunit—the reason for it—
is a different matter.
Precisely. And therein lies the key
to cracking this case.
In any event, first I'll need more information.
I'm going out for a bit.
Wait for me! I'll accompany you.
Yes, my father was in perfect health.
Although he was a heavy smoker,
everyone who knew him agreed he seemed exceptionally youthful for his age.
As he was so fond of saying,
"The span of one man's life is far too brief to reach the Root."
Reaching the Root is what every magus dreams of.
It's for that reason that magi engrave the sum of their knowledge into magic crests,
and pass them on so their descendants
draw ever closer to that goal.
There was nothing my father wanted more than to arrive at the Root himself.
I can't believe he'd ever take his own life.
Interesting. Then I presume the research Sir Ernest was conducting was to the same end?
Yes. My father had long been fond of speaking about eternity.
Eternity...
He sought something everlasting.
I never had any reason to doubt his words were the truth.
Until I came to know you, Professor.
Me?
"Since ancient times, mankind thought the stars eternal.
But we have come to know that this isn't true."
As you know, the refutation of the Ptolemaic theory of geocentrism in the 17th century
overturned the foundation of astromancy that came before.
Yes.
"Not even the stars' luster can last forever."
I expected nothing less of you, Professor.
I could say the same of you. I see you remember my lectures down to the last detail.
From the time you first joined my class,
I knew how exceptionally talented you were.
I've had my eye on this place for a long time.
It's a mother lode of valuable grimoires,
and selling them's gonna make me rich.
Who gives a damn about hunting for the killer?
What a load of bull.
I'm so close to being able to join all the pieces.
Master, there's something I've been wondering.
What was it that troubled you about the hallway?
Oh yes, that.
Let's put things in order.
As I've said in class,
each part of the human body
corresponds to one of the seven greater planets.
Right.
For example,
Mars corresponds to the head.
Mercury, the chest and arms.
The Sun, the heart.
Fargo's head, upper body, neck, arms, and heart were discovered in the hall,
his bones and hair in the library,
and his legs in the storeroom.
You said the arrangement of the parts didn't
match up with any known theory of magecraft.
That's right.
The decisive feature was the way his heart,
which corresponds to the Sun,
was placed in the center of the rotunda.
Was there something off about it being in the center?
Magecraft of this type is configured to place the magus in the center,
and the tools for carrying out the spell
in the surrounding area.
But in the center of this room is the corpse's heart.
Almost like the dead man himself were casting spells! What a lark!
What's the matter, Master?
Lord! Something frightful has happened!
Alec! Who could have done this?!
By the time I found him, he was already like this.
My my, another murder.
This is turning into something out of a penny dreadful.
Hey! I smell something!
Who was that?
If Add is reacting, that means...
Yes. He's sensed a spirit of the dead
haunting this place.
A spirit?!
Those bones and hair symbolize Saturn, which governs the realm of the dead.
The lingering Saturnian mana drew the spirit to this place.
Necromancy.
Your specialty, as I recall.
What utter nonsense. Are you accusing me
of bringing that spirit here?
No. But it's clear that your research is being applied.
My research?!
We're returning to the hall.
I'll explain everything there.
Well?
Professor, who is the culprit?
Let me start from the beginning.
First, the magecraft cast over this house
is indeed utilizing the seven greater planets.
It was for this reason that the body was dismembered and placed throughout its rooms.
Oh, come now. Haven't we told you
again and again why that's impossible?
That was the pitfall that tripped up all of us.
A pitfall?
Being of the Animusphere family,
you all adhere closely to Ptolemaic theory when invoking astromancy.
Am I correct?
That's right. The heliocentric model of magecraft that posits Earth should not be central
is nothing but a newfangled modern theory!
It goes against all our family's traditions.
Yes. It would run counter to the aesthetics prized by the Animusphere family.
But within your family was someone who had abandoned those beliefs.
Ernest Fargo himself.
What?!
He had theories, aesthetics, and values of his own.
And a dream he was driven to realize, no matter how he had to twist them.
As I thought.
Th-This can't be!
The heart, which symbolizes the Sun,
was placed in the very center of the manor.
In concentric circles around it, the arms, symbolizing Mercury, and the neck, symbolizing Venus.
And after the Sun, Mercury, and Venus, next would be...
Earth?
Precisely.
But there is no part of the human body corresponding to the Earth.
Earth corresponds instead to the soul.
That's why I was sure something
containing his soul had to be right here.
I knew it!
This entire house was your atelier, built for you to achieve eternal life!
Father!
Oh Mary, my dear daughter.
Give me your life!
I still require more to achieve eternity.
More life...
More knowledge...
More power!
Phwoar! You've stepped deep in it this time!
Father...
Why?
The ritual is still incomplete.
The spell was experimental, using none of your family's traditions or knowledge for its foundation.
Naturally, it's incredibly unstable.
But what he sought was not merely to prolong his life.
It was immortality!
Ernest!
Unlike other magi, he never intended to entrust his dream to the next generation.
He sought to reach the Root himself by any means necessary.
So he built this mansion as his own heliocentric model of the heavens and the Earth,
and for the seven planets he scattered his own dismembered body through it.
Ernest, what have you done?
By doing this, he meant to merge
with the cosmos that is this house,
and become an eternal being!
My dream...
The Root!
I will reach it!
Master, I think he's beyond saving.
I know.
Gray. Can I leave this to you?
Yes.
Hey! What is she doing?
It's too dangerous to face alone!
We have to help her!
There's no need.
In fact, we'd better step back.
We don't want to get in her way!
Add!
At your service!
First Stage!
Rescind Restraints!
It can't be!
An Anti-Undead Mystic Code!
Well, ain't this lovely! An all-you-can-eat buffet!
Gray.
Rave.
Crave.
Deprave.
It's eating the mana right out of the air!
Just who on earth is this apprentice of yours, Professor?!
You think to destroy me?
I am eternal!
Grave, me.
Grave for you.
Everything will be all right now.
Let the central branch of the family handle the rest.
Thank you for all you've done for us.
It was nothing, really.
Still, I can't believe he'd venture
to test such incomplete magecraft.
To achieve eternal life
was my father's dearest wish.
There's one more deduction
I didn't mention in front of the others.
Yes, Professor?
Mary. You knew all along, didn't you?
That your father's ritual was doomed to fail.
You're an exceptionally talented magus.
Even if he didn't tell you the full scope of his plans,
you were more than capable of figuring out the nature of his research and his objective.
Of course, I know you had no wish
to kill him yourself.
However, you also made no attempt to stop him
from conducting the incomplete ritual you knew would end his life.
Am I right?
If you were, what would you do next?
I'd do nothing.
There's nothing I could do.
I don't have a shred of evidence.
This is no more than a hypothesis.
But the whydunit—
the reason you'd do this.
That I'm still curious about.
If my father managed to achieve immortality,
I knew nothing would ever change for me again.
I would have remained captive inside the cage that is this manor for the rest of my life.
All I did was to prove to him
that nothing is eternal.
Just as you taught me, Professor.
Thank you, Professor. I'm so grateful to you.
Please, be well.
"Nothing is eternal. All things change."
"Humans are no exception," eh?
Master?
Let's go back home.
Yes, sir.