I...
I want to see you one more time.
I want to grant you your wish.
But that wish no longer...
Master...
It would be okay if you came out to laugh at me and say, "You fledgling!"
But I know...
You'd tell me to awkwardly struggle until the very end, right?
I'll do it...
because I am one of your loyal subjects.
Is that you, Reines?
Yeah, we have no choice.
I will bow my head down to Sir Sophia-Ri.
I need to resolve a complicated situation over at Spiritual Evocation, right?
My, oh my.
This is perfect.
I want to ask you something.
Oh no, it won't take too much of your time.
Why can't you, Professor?
I'm not good enough?
I'm sorry. I do find you to be very charming.
Are you in love with someone?
Yeah.
Well, I guess you could say that.
Isn't it about time, Primary Lecturer Wills?
Sorry to show you such a big mess.
You still are popular with the girls as always.
Good thinking though to leave the door open
when you'll be alone with a female student.
Sorry to trouble you, Lord.
No, pardon me.
Is this the first time we've spoken like this since your father's funeral?
I finally got all personal affairs in order.
Sir Trevor Pelham Codrington was a grand Necromancer.
Once again, I give you my condolences.
So, what did you want to ask of me as one of the authorities in Spiritual Evocation?
Five years ago, my father purchased wasteland,
including a whole ancient Roman monument.
The Marbury Workshop.
Transforming an entire wasteland into a Workshop,
the strength of its magical energy rivals that of a shrine.
However, the Marbury Workshop ran out of control.
With a series of lightning falling, not only did all the family Magi perish,
but more than a dozen local civilian lives were lost.
And the last casualty was my father.
It was caused by a leyline becoming warped.
You already know that much?
For Magical Workshops of that style,
it's hard to think of other sources of magical energy.
But it's strange that someone as prolific as Sir Trevor couldn't repair it.
If accidents at the Workshop continue,
there's nothing I can do anymore.
In other words, elder brother,
if this continues,
the Marbury Workshop will be taken up by the main Codrington family, land and all.
I see. But if a Workshop of that caliber is confiscated,
it would hurt Bram, as well, huh?
I also have one more thing I needed to consult you on.
I'll talk about that on-site.
Understood.
I will take care of this case.
I'm grateful you egged him on, Princess of El-Melloi.
But of course.
If it's for the next department head
of Spiritual Evocation,
my elder brother vows to even pull chestnuts out of the fire as needed.
What beautiful sisterly love you have.
But is he still obsessed with that ritual?
Holy Grail War, was it?
Yes.
The Clock Tower is sending Atrum Galliasta
and Bazett Fraga McRemitz.
But there still is a slot left.
At least, that's what my elder brother believes.
If I were to mediate, I could probably shove him into the McRemitz slot.
But to think someone who is at least temporarily a Lord
to bow down to me for a shady ritual like that...
Come now. The previous Lord El-Melloi and your little sister
both died in a shady Holy Grail War, didn't they?
Are you saying I should mourn?
Surely not.
They say you shrivel up without any curiosity.
Damn that lass.
So, can you finally talk to me about this?
This is essentially within Spiritual Evocation's jurisdiction.
So, why me?
That's because...
The main Codrington family filed a complaint about this to the Policies Department.
To Policies?
They said that the Workshop is unstable because of me,
and at this rate, it will breach Concealment of the Mystics,
so the main family needs to manage it.
And that would be troublesome for that guy Bram.
But Spiritual Evocation openly meddling in an inheritance dispute
would give them a bad rep.
All right. I was the one set to doing Sir Sophia-Ri a favor.
I'll do anything it takes...
if it means I can participate in a Holy Grail War once again!
Miss Reines?
Here, take this.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I have to endure it for a little while.
It's nothing much.
It seems the leyline balance is less stable than I thought.
She has Mystic Eyes?
Yes. When Reines comes in contact with magical energy, her eyes turn red.
But it's not often that pain accompanies it.
It feels like back when I was younger when I stuck my hand into the fireplace.
Though, I'll be okay as long as I use some eye drops.
It might be better for us to hurry.
Master?
The wind elements are moving furiously.
A storm is coming.
Are you all right, Lord?
I-I didn't think we'd be walking such a long distance.
You're still a frail little boy.
Indeed, a little boy.
Who is a little boy?
You have finally returned.
Hold it.
I didn't think you'd already be over here.
Miss Adashino.
It's been a while, Lord El-Melloi II.
As long as a complaint has been filed,
it is the duty of Policies to promptly carry out an investigation.
And as a result of that investigation...
It can't be!
Yes.
Wills Pelham Codrington is under arrest as a suspect in the murder of Sir Trevor.
H-Hold on just a minute!
How did things end up that way?
Oh?
Shut up, you father-killer!
W-Waletta!
Miss Adashino, who is she?
She is Waletta Codrington,
sent from the main Codrington family of Necromancy to ascertain the situation.
Upon arrival,
I immediately tried calling down
Sir Trevor to learn his circumstances.
But all traces of him were gone!
I see. That's quite the tale.
Master, what does that mean?
Calling someone down with Necromancy
is summoning the residual thoughts of the dead.
However, not all who have died can be called down.
The residual thoughts can wear down, or the communication can be disturbed.
Erasing all traces of him is a serious matter.
Right. To erase all traces of residual thoughts
is similar to someone wiping away fingerprints in a criminal investigation.
That's right!
And it can only be done...
by a Necromancer!
Stop. That is only circumstantial evidence.
You are ignoring the possibility of other perpetrators.
We're not talking just Sir Trevor!
I failed to call down everyone involved in these accidents involving lightning!
And every time lightning has fallen, Wills was present within the mansion!
It's a misunderstanding, Waletta!
It's true that I tried to call down the soul of my father.
But I failed!
And can you prove that?
Well, that...
I believe all of this evidence will be enough.
Wait just a minute.
Oh? Are you saying a great detective is entering the scene again?
Just look outside.
In this storm, it's dangerous to drive a car.
And all this lightning...
Surely you haven't forgotten how Sir Trevor passed away.
You mean, at the least, we're riveted here until this storm passes.
That's right.
Therefore, Miss Adashino,
I would like permission to investigate this Workshop until the storm passes.
That's nonsense!
Modern Magecraft Theory dares trample upon Spiritual Evocation matters?
Unfortunately for you, the Spiritual Evocation
Department requested this of us.
We'll share what we find with both Policies and the main Codrington family.
How does that sound?
Oh, all right.
Miss Hishiri?
Since he can't escape anyway, it's useless to restrict him.
Thank you so much.
Oh? You haven't been cleared of your suspicion yet.
Whether or not you're the perpetrator will come into light with the investigation, correct?
Yes. That's correct.
I won't pass judgement on anything that has yet to be proven.
That is the way of a scholar.
This is my father's study.
Please feel free to look around.
Thank you.
How are you related to that young lady Waletta?
She's a childhood friend from the main family.
A lot of things happened, and she hates me.
Did you refuse to marry her?
Correct! What a brilliant detective!
If you're sentenced by Policies,
she'll likely take over this Workshop.
Yes.
Such a transparent picture to paint sounds like something she'd do.
And what about you? How are you related to Miss Adashino?
There was something in the past.
We have the worst compatibility in all of the Clock Tower.
Now, can you finally talk to me...
about the other reason why you called me here?
Yes. It seems she is here right now.
Here?
Excuse me.
Is that...
a Fairy?
Yes.
She seems to be a Fairy rooted to this land.
She disappeared?
She started to appear around when the Workshop was complete.
That day was also stormy like today.
You can see Fairies.
Fairy Eyes, huh?
It's not that strong for Mystic Eyes,
but I was born with them.
And every time she gives me a warning, someone dies.
Then...
I want to know...
what she is warning me against.
The Wild Hunt...
An order of Fairy knights?
Miss Reines, it's not good to investigate the mansion without permission.
We should head back.
Oh?
What's this magical energy?
A hidden corridor!
We're getting into the swing of things!
You shouldn't! We need to inform Master!
And if we do that, Adashino will catch on, as well.
We need to investigate this first.
Besides, it's my principle to voluntarily do things others don't want to do.
This feels familiar.
I can tell because I'm a grave-keeper.
This is a graveyard.
After all, these are ruins a Necromancer purchased.
This must be the main keep for the Magical Workshop.
That's strange.
It's too soon for the eye drops to lose effect!
I see. These ruins are creating a response from my Mystic Eyes!
Let's head back!
Yeah.
That's not it.
These ruins are drawing out the power of my Mystic Eyes.
If that's so—
Look out!
Gray!
Hey there, missies.
You guys okay?
Y-Yes!
And you are...
These are spirits who were guarding the graveyard.
It seems they perceive you missies as grave robbers.
They're not wrong per se.
Well, damn.
They're getting even more excited now.
I know a secret passageway back out.
It will be slightly rough for an escort.
Think you missies can keep up?
Yes.
Reines!
She's fine.
She's just passed out.
And you are...
He was the one who saved her.
Shishigou Kairi.
A Necromancer and a mercenary.
Originally from Japan,
he accepts even the dirtiest of jobs.
He's quite famous over at Policies.
I recall I still had a seat in the Clock Tower for now.
And what is a celebrity like him here for?
Mr. Shishigou is one of my father's friends.
I came here to express my condolences.
And? You didn't even show up at the mansion.
What was a visitor doing in the graveyard?
That graveyard is connected to the bottom of the hill.
It was more convenient to pass through there to avoid lightning in getting here.
So I see.
And there's this storm.
Wills, kiddo, is the room I usually use still left as is?
Yes. I'll show you the way.
Seriously, why are we in the same room?
I believe it's optimal for bearing children.
Ch... Wh-Why such a thought?
Unfortunately, your magic circuits are complete garbage of course.
Wha...
But it's not a bad seed for a successor.
It's not a bad idea to use this opportunity to set it up, right?
Give me a break!
Shut up and go to sleep!
Jeez! You still can't take a joke, can you?
If you have that much energy, I guess you're all right.
The underground graveyard was a hive of spirits, but this bed is nice.
The leyline of this land reacts with Mystic Eyes.
Thunder, Mystic Eyes, graveyard...
I need just a little more for everything to connect.
That's it!
What's the matter?
There's something I need to confirm.
Listen to what Gray says and be a good girl by staying in bed.
Got that?
What is the meaning of this, Hishiri?
Of what?
Don't play dumb with me.
Why is Modern Magecraft Theory intervening?
It's nothing to worry about.
I can't afford to hand this Workshop over to the likes of Bram!
For us Magi, the howdunit and the whodunit are both meaningless.
Because all of that can be decided for by all of us in Policies.
Is the warped image the correct one or is it mistaken?
That is what we determine.
So,
please rest assured.
Just as I thought.
And if that's the case...
Master! Master!
What's wrong, Gray?
It's terrible!
Miss Waletta was struck by lightning!
We have yet another casualty?