I hear the Zoology Department is in quite a stir over this.
To think Lord Khaladron would meet his end
by the hand of an assassin.
And the vultures are already circling with their eyes on the position he left vacant.
They're in such a frenzy that even the likes of my dear brother are being sought for help.
What does the man himself say?
My brother scarcely spares a thought for anything but his obsession with the Grail War, as usual.
The Greater Grail of Fuyuki, was it?
A ritual in which seven magi
summon seven Servants
and go to war, with an omnipotent
wish-granting artifact as the prize.
Does he seek a rematch for the events of ten years past, or revenge for Kayneth?
A curious fellow, either way.
Something the matter?
Not a thing. I simply find it strange.
What's this?
This Greater Grail.
If it truly existed, I'd think it would be a topic of much greater interest,
even if it took place in a Far East backwater.
For an incident that lead to the death of a Lord,
it's been kept suspiciously quiet, true.
I speak of your Spiritual Evocation Department in particular,
since the director's daughter was also among the deceased.
So you believe someone's trying to sweep it under the rug?
This is all purely supposition.
Though if you hadn't arrived at the same conclusion,
I'd daresay you were losing your touch.
In any event, it's time we put my dear brother through some pain and suffering.
Ouch! Ouch!
Flatt, you dullard!
But I didn't have any rock salt!
What's wrong with using pyrite instead?
Absolutely everything!
This lesson is on creating bounded fields!
What kind of idiot would
create a spell to break them?
True, both rock salt and pyrite are composed of cubic crystals
and correspond to the First Territory of earth,
but pyrite is also fire elemental, as the "pyre"
within its name should have made perfectly obvious!
Ooh, here it comes! The Iron Claw of Death!
Bring that into your ritual,
and forget the bounded field—
Take me now, Professor!
you'd unbalance the surrounding mana completely and send it out of control!
He's no match for Fritz Von Erich on the technique front, though.
Moreover, combining pyrite and nitric acid gives you nitrous oxide! Which would poison even you!
You're quite the pro-wrestling buff.
There's no more appropriate diversion for a well-bred lady than wrestling.
Though I must say,
Uncle, Sir! Uncle!
You careless clod!
Why do you insist on wasting your talent bedeviling me?
If I'd possessed abilities like yours when I was a lad—
I could have been awesome!
Master...
Ahem.
Now, where was I?
Ah. On maintaining equilibrium in the territory of justice—
Just what was that display of Lord El-Melloi's about?
I-I'm sorry.
Is this the sort of lecture I came here all the way from Finland to audit?
I'd hardly call that fitting conduct
for the tutor of Luviagelita Edelfelt!
What became of the brilliance I witnessed during the Adra Castle Separation case?
Answer me, Gray.
T-To tell the truth...
His favorite café closed?!
Yes. Master is quite partial to that tearoom,
but they've been closed due to electrical problems.
I'd heard the Brits enjoy their teatime,
but this seems quite the extreme reaction.
There's nowhere else near Master's home that serves meals as well, you see.
He depends on it as a place to write his papers,
and he sends myself there to buy his lunches.
Without that café,
he's quite unable to get any work done.
That's the reason?
I can think of no more embarrassing admission
in the Clock Tower's history!
But he said he was going to the shop this evening to try and figure out their problems,
so that should be that.
I quite fervently hope so!
Honestly now.
Reines?
Might I borrow you for a bit, young Lady Edelfelt?
I'd like to have a chat about the Grail War.
What an awful state of affairs.
I'm thinking it was rats.
It seems to be leaking current.
I don't even want to think about
what our next electric bill will look like.
Rodentia...
Well, never mind that.
What say the council?
We've contacted them about it.
But who knows when they'll
find the time to come round?
We had exterminators out here too, but...
What happened?
One went missing,
and the second quit on the spot,
babbling about having seen something terrible in there.
I see.
Well, let me have a look.
Bestial magecraft, I see.
So this is where the electricity is leaking.
Or rather, where it is being drawn.
A furred animal, electricity, and the color blue...
I see.
Have you made any headway?
Yes. I've more or less figured out the cause.
I'll go down and investigate.
We can't ask a university professor to dig around under the city.
Not to mention you could be terribly injured!
As long as this café remains closed,
my students will have to bear far worse.
This aqueduct must date back to
at least the 19th century.
Rather larger than I expected.
I spoke too soon. It seems to be growing larger still.
A thunder barrier?
No doubt about it.
Some magus has an atelier here.
A sewer waterway, a workshop, and thunder...
How nostalgic.
Master...
Hello?
What? It's Master?
Whoa! This sure is something, freshie!
So this is what an "internet" is!
It's Caules, yeah? Your machine is ace!
Oh, it's nothing special, really.
It's a damn sight less scary than Flatt's computer!
Hey guys! You called?
Wow! Now that's a top-of-the-line PC!
It is?
You've got multiple monitors 'n everything!
That's a sweet case too!
Did you build it yourself?
Ah, yeah.
It's optimized for searches
and database maintenance.
Monitors're connected via LAN.
Whoa, killer! What're the specs on your graphics card?
Oh.
Hiya, this is Flatt.
Well, hi there, Gray!
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Did you just say "Gray"?
Hm? The Prof hasn't come back?
I've just had a call from the café.
They said he went down into their sewer and never came out again!
All righty then!
Don't you fret. Leave everything to me.
I'll be there in a jiff!
Bye now!
Why?!
Why would Milady Gray call you when I'm right here?
Explain yourself!
How dare you keep the sound of that angelic voice for yourself?
Knock it off! Or at least watch out for my computer!
I'm begging you, stop!
What went on between you and my delightfully gentle, mellow, sorta yellow-scented Milady Gray?
If you must know...
Say it!
It's probably 'cause I have a cell phone
and you don't, Le Chien.
G-Good point.
A phone... If I only had a phone...
I could hear her voice anytime!
I'll go set up a phone plan at once!
Stay, little doggie.
The shops are all closed at this hour anyhow.
Ah! Milady! Milady!
Let's go.
Milady!
Honestly, Fiore,
I'm starting to have second thoughts about enrolling here.
Well? Smell anything familiar?
Yes! That wonderful smell could only be yours, Milady.
So tender and so...
delicious!
Down, boy.
Remember, Professor told you
to keep your distance from her.
I-I'm sorry, Miss Gray.
N-Not at all.
I smell the Professor!
Master!
It fed off the electricity down here
until it grew to a truly monstrous size.
I thought I could dispel it, but...
In a contest of pure power,
I'm simply no match for it.
Where is it now?
I managed to drive it away.
I'd like to say I gave as good as I got, but...
I don't think it will stay away for long.
It was...
Flatt.
Remember the mana balance...
Master!
Don't worry. He's only passed out.
I suppose we'll have to take it from here.
Yep!
Okay then, Le Chien,
you get the Professor to a hospital.
Why me?!
And quit calling me that!
If we're going up against a spectral thingy,
we need Gray to stay here.
And don't forget what the Prof told you
about hanging around her.
All right already.
But you'd better make sure she doesn't get hurt.
Not a scratch!
You can count on me!
Ah...
What's up?
Does Mister Svin have something against me, perhaps?
Huh?
I so often find him glaring at me,
and whenever he sees me,
he starts breathing quite hard,
and seems rather riled up...
Oh, that.
I definitely don't think he has anything against you, Gray.
Is that so?
He's an awkward sort and doesn't quite know what to do with himself, that's all.
Though if I said that to his face, I'd be done for.
Take my case.
No one, at home or the Clock Tower,
ever pays me any mind.
But the Professor and the rest of the class rag on me constantly for being an idiot.
That was the first time anyone ever
treated me like a person.
Like... a person?
And I'm not the only one.
That goes for Le Chien,
and all our classmates besides.
If it weren't for the Professor,
nobody would ever see us
as anything but wash-outs.
You're right. Master truly sees us for who we are.
So, y'see, that's just the way Le Chien is.
And I'm the way I am.
That's just something you gotta accept, right?
Wow, that was pretty profound of me!
Right then, let's exterminate whatever this thingy is and bring the Professor home.
Yes, let's go.
Is that you, Svin?
Professor! Don't try to speak.
I'm calling for a doctor now.
Forget the doctor. Give that phone here.
There's someone I must tell of this.
Goodness...
Well, I think we found that missing exterminator.
Lookie here! Stripped the flesh clean off his bones, didn't it?
That one over there, too.
We're right in the beastie's larder.
Looks like it's home.
We've found it.
Let's do it! Just like we planned, 'kay?
Okay!
Gotcha!
Now!
First Stage, Rescind Restraints!
Phwoar.
What happened?
Just what Professor said would happen.
The bounded field was being powered by the underground mana and this thingy,
so if we release the restrictions on the flow
and turn it back on itself...
It must be past here.
Yep. This way to its warren.
Let's go!
This is the workshop of a magus, isn't it?
Looks like Peter Rabbit hippity-hopped out of here.
It's taking the food it pilfered home to its master.
Food?
Not sure exactly what it is, but I'll bet it's awful grisly!
Would you, now?
You've got quite the nerve,
bringing nuisance to my door.
Hiya! Sorry 'bout the intrusion!
I take it you didn't hear our knock?
You would dare intrude upon
the atelier of Gurdoa Davenant
and make foolish jokes besides?
What common whelp might you be?
Common whelps from the class of Lord El-Melloi II, sir!
I'm Flatt Escardos, and the lady is Gray!
Lord El-Melloi II?
That upstart with his nonsensical "Modern Magecraft" theories?
Don't you dare insult him! Thank you!
Insult him?
Our Professor's not just any upstart!
He gained the status of Lord in a single generation!
He's the uppest start in the whole Clock Tower!
And now the pupils of that
upstart have come here
with an eye to destroying
the products of my research, is that it?
That monster has taken innocent lives!
Innocent?
The common rabble should be honored
to die by the thousands
to become the lamp oil
which will light my path to the Root!
You would infiltrate my workshop merely to spout such trifling sentimentality?
Whoa!
The weight of one human life
is heavier than the Earth, y'know!
And they're an unexpectedly inefficient fuel source—
I am no mere murderer!
Their deaths are a means to a far greater end!
Your master won't be coming
to save you uneducated whelps this time.
When you've been torn limb from limb,
innards spilled on the ground,
I will lay bare the sins of your mentor
to the scorn of all!
And his "modern magecraft" will be exposed for the charlatanry that it is!
Hm, don't like the looks of this much.
Okay, I'll stay here and create a diversion while you escape!
But what about you?
I've always wanted to say that!
That won't be necessary.
Ooh!
Ouch!
Must you overdo everything, Svin?
Sorry, but you're the one who ordered me
to get us here as fast as physically possible.
Well, can't deny that.
So you must be Lord El-Melloi II.
And you would be Sir Gurdoa Davenant.
Indeed.
Have you come to apologize for
the ill manners of your apprentices?
Surely you jest.
I am here to censure you for your many crimes.
I'll also be rescuing my pupils while I'm at it.
My crimes?
Your magecraft made use of lightning and a furred animal,
both with the aspect of Jupiter.
How did you know that?!
You utilized a Phantasmal Species with the factor of Jupiter,
your rabbit beast, and had it draw in electricity until you could transmute its power
to that of Zeus, the god of thunder.
This altar is a Mystic Code you created so you could use people as puppets!
You would dare...
I'm aware that the jockeying to succeed the murdered
Zoology Department head is at a fever pitch.
You thought gaining the power of Zeus
would put you first in the running, didn't you?
How do you know all this?
I know! You thought to use your apprentices to steal my research, didn't you?!
Who put you up to this?
Oh, do be quiet.
The rankest amateur would be able to tell with one look—
even a talentless pretender to the title of Lord like me.
In fact, all the evidence is right here:
in the electric meter readings.
They're off the charts.
You consumed as much as a small factory.
Oh, I get it! That's the juice these electro-bunnies were drinking!
In a manner of speaking.
And here's a local newspaper article
on the serial murders.
"Disappearances on Druid Street."
"Has Jack the Ripper returned from the grave?!"
What of it?
You might have gone undetected in the 20th century,
but we live in an information society now.
It was only a matter of time
before someone put the pieces together and saw what you were up to.
Sir Gurdoa, I hereby take you into custody.
You have violated the Clock Tower's
most stringent taboo
against revealing the secrets of magecraft.
I've done practically nothing!
Practically nothing, you hear me?
Do you suggest such a paltry experiment could expose the Mystics?
I strongly advise you not to attempt that!
The Policies Department has already moved to indict you,
and the Zoology Department has approved it!
The rest of Zoology, I might add,
was absolutely delighted to see you lose your seat.
My...
My magecraft...
My grand Mystic Code!
This would have been a trifling matter
one hundred years ago!
Your attitude towards magecraft is a relic of those hundred years.
Such are the times we now live in.
We of Norwich are here to bring magecraft into a harmonious existence with the modern era.
I'm quite thankful...
Eh?
...that he didn't realize how much of that was a bluff.
If Gurdoa had decided to resort to brute force,
I'd really have been up the creek.
Really?
I was convinced you had something up your sleeve.
"To steal away in the night
is the act of a thief and a coward."
"But to stride away boldly with your voice raised in song?
That is how a King of Conquerors departs the field."
Hm, don't think I've seen that movie.
It's something a great idiot said to me once.
Sometimes, taking decisive action yields more than mere material...
rewards...
Master!
But I've definitely had enough.
I'm not cut out for heroics...
like this...
You worked very hard indeed today, Sir.
Eat to your hearts' content!
It's thanks to you that we're open again, Professor.
I didn't know the university faculty
were such accomplished ratcatchers!
I'm a man of many talents.
Delicious!
This'll give me the energy I need for my paper!
My brother's brain is a device of no great complexity.
Shut it!
You came all the way over here to
interrupt my lunch! What do you want?!
Don't you think it's considerate of us
to bring you the results of Luvia's search in person?
Though I'm afraid it's all bad news.
Hm?
Concerning the Holy Grail War.
The two positions open to Association participants
have already been filled.