What in the world is that Servant?
She's Iskandar's primary confidante.
That's why I'm troubled.
I don't recall seeing her among those in Ionioi Hetairoi.
One who accompanied the King of Conquerors,
a comrade in arms who shared his dream,
should be fighting alongside him after death as a Heroic Spirit.
And yet...
Waver!
Welcome back!
Just as you asked, I arranged for the auction to be delayed!
Imperfections in the catalog, delays in the train...
He attacked from every front. He was on a rampage.
As I needed to add extra funding, I wrung in a deal to delay the auction as much as possible!
A habitual complainer...
They said they would push the start to midnight tonight.
So, half a day left.
Yes. Shishigou's report is just like what I had Gray tell you.
Oh no, thank you for the hard work.
You may be recovering from illness, but I do anticipate your active role in the situation.
You're wondering if I'm enjoying this?
Of course I am!
We've already decided that Karabo was the perpetrator, right?
It's not set in stone yet.
And...
the perpetrator for this case is clearly my enemy.
The perpetrator for this case?
Do you mean the one who killed Trisha?
The one who stole the relic from you?
The Master of that Heroic Spirit?
Without a doubt, all three are the same person.
I would like to ask you for help once again.
Hey, why do I have to do something like that?
I hate all of you!
I hate people who look like they were recognized for their efforts!
I hate self-conclusive people who think they don't have to be recognized by others!
You look like you fit into both of those categories!
You're the worst of the worst! I detest you!
Master isn't saying that—
What he does is no different!
Because you guys are trying to stand up against her!
Looking at that makes me feel miserable!
Miss Olga Marie...
You guys are up against Policies!
They only think of all of us as pawns!
I know that.
Even then, with what's behind all that,
I will fight!
I hate more than anything how I can't completely reject you guys and your ways.
You are courageous.
Let me tell you an old story.
I stole that relic.
Instead of training to build my pathetic self up to confront my mentor,
I had the misconception that I could have him recognize me with stolen powers.
I didn't have courage, like you do now,
to throw my own feelings at the face of an adult.
I am simply a survivor.
It's not like I'm standing up against anything.
It's just harder for me to stay crouching.
Master...
This time,
I want to win for sure.
Because the perpetrator for this case ended up being my enemy,
I can't lose against him at any cost!
Don't you want to win, Olga Marie?
Don't you want to prove to the world
that you won't simply cry yourself to sleep
when someone murders your attendant?
You just called me "Olga Marie."
Not as "Animusphere" or "the Lord's daughter."
That's right. I need you.
Don't forget, Lord El-Melloi II, this is a deal.
I can feel the exhaust shaking my stomach!
American cars really are great!
More like, were you really sent here by Reines, Mr. Shishigou?
Yeah, that's right! Can you finally tell us why you pulled us out of our special lecture?
A moving car is a boundary between the living world and the underworld.
It creates a pseudo-enclosed space both physically and spiritually.
It should be okay now.
That is your new assignment.
I see. This truly is...
Yeah. This job is suited for us, Flatt!
The Greater Grail of Fuyuki is useless?
Yes.
Dad had said that in the past.
As far as I am aware,
that Greater Grail is genuine no matter how you think about it.
Otherwise,
it wouldn't be able to summon Heroic Spirits.
Like I would know.
That was my dad's conclusions for calling off going to the Holy Grail War.
Trisha was looking into the Holy Grail War. It was because...
she wanted to know why your father stopped loving you.
Trisha did?
And chasing after your father's source of information,
she was murdered.
It seems like illusions.
You mean the Holy Grail War?
Everything.
Your Holy Grail War,
the Child of Ainnash,
this Mystic Eyes Collection Train,
memories of Trisha...
They all feel like scenery left behind.
The host has long since gone walking yonder,
but the shadow is still left behind in present time.
Why is everyone desperately holding on,
knowing that there's only the shadow left?
It's like an afterimage.
Oh, that's it.
Master?
You are truly the heir of Animusphere.
Do those eyes have a birds-eye view of the world?
Wh-What? Don't compliment me all of a sudden!
Oh no, you're worthy of praise as an individual.
I need to contact someone.
I'll be right back.
This is Luviagelita. Who is this?
It's me.
I heard you've been assisting Reines.
I give my thanks.
It is all fine as I've been remunerated.
Or is this an additional request?
It is. How did Lord Animusphere get to know of the Holy Grail War?
Even in the Clock Tower,
a surprisingly few magi even noticed that event.
There are traces of someone controlling the information.
Looking at how Adashino has been reacting, I don't think it was Policies. However,
there's no doubt that someone got Animusphere moving.
And Trisha was investigating it when she was killed.
You may have forgotten,
but I'm not a member of the El-Melloi Classroom.
I've simply hired you as a personal tutor.
When the Holy Grail War is over, I promise to give you personal lectures.
I'll make sure to wring out all your secrets when you do.
For us, the Edelfelt family, to intervene in conflict to make the greatest profit...
It's finally time to show what we can really do!
Bright.
This is an artificial environmental model created by Animusphere.
Is this enough?
Yeah.
With a leyline map this accurate.
I see. I get it.
It's only a matter of what order.
I finally caught you this time!
Why didn't I notice this?
This is a not a mystery at all!
Why Hephaestion was female or why she wasn't in Ionioi Hetairoi are not the issues!
The question is...
why did that thing claim to be Hephaestion?
The whydunit.
This is no true case.
It's the afterimage of what was once a case.
No, it's a remnant that sees even less salvation than that.
What in the world are you talking about?
Now, the final part.
Miss Adashino had been hiding it,
but other than Trisha Fellows' severed head,
wasn't there something else hidden within the imaginary space?
This fell out along with Trisha's head.
This is what I saw!
As expected. Damn Adashino!
She removed it from her deduction as the puzzle pieces wouldn't fit with this.
Will that become the key to reaching the true perpetrator?
Yes.
The deductions made by Policies will completely be overturned.
Everyone, we will begin the Mystic Eyes Auction shortly.
Please head over to the Warehouse for a Myriad of Mystic Eyeballs, the Pandemonium.
25 million dollars.
30 million dollars.
40 million dollars!
Sold for 40 million dollars.
Nothing less from an authority on Mystic Eyes.
She doesn't hold back for notable Mystic Eyes.
And lastly,
our main item for this auction!
These are the Jewel-class Mystic Eyes of Transience.
We will start at 30 million dollars.
40 million.
50 million!
70 million!
80 million!
90 million!
100 million!
Even a Picasso piece is worth that much.
If it's Jewel-class Mystic Eyes, it won't end at this level.
130 million.
Oh no, no, no! Policies has to be joking about this!
I'm serious of course.
140 million.
150 million.
160 million.
200 million!
230 million.
230 million. Going once!
Going twice!
240 million!
What's wrong?
I said, "240 million dollars."
Auctioneer,
I would like you to please keep going.
Well then...
Hold on!
This is heating up way too much!
Auctioneer, let us take a break!
Motion accepted.
What's the meaning of this, Waver?
You can't possibly get that much money ready in your current state!
But you were about to stand down at 230 million!
All things considered...
Though, that said, I'm dubious of Yvette's wallet, too.
Then, how much can Policies spend?
They don't care how much they spend.
Those Mystic Eyes are under Policies' management now.
The money from the successful bid isn't going to Karabo but to Policies.
They can pay hundreds of millions of dollars,
and it all goes back to them?
Of course, there are limits to how much money Adashino can move at her discretion,
and some money will be taken as commission so it won't make a clear profit.
But it's a shrewd plan suited to her nature.
And what are you after, Waver?
Will you seriously go against how much funding Policies has?
The enemy probably didn't expect the prices to go this high.
He surely has to be concentrating during the auction.
That's when I'll ready my trump card.
This is quite an expensive diversion you've got here!
You could buy a stealth fighter with it!
Hey, Waver,
let me ask you again.
Can you promise me that this will be amusing?
Is this an act worthy of putting a friend's financial ruin on the line?
Can you swear that it is?
I promise you it will surely be to your liking.
All right, then!
Oh, it's me. Yeah, me.
Remember the tuning machine you've been wanting? No, I won't sell it.
But if I use it as collateral, how much can you dish out?
30 million dollars? No, that's not gonna fly!
You should at least be able to go 70 million!
Well, I don't have much time,
so we can compromise, and I'll settle for 50 million.
We'll go with that.
Okay! You have 130 million extra now!
Will we be able to fight now?
By the way, Gray, Reines entrusted you with a card, didn't she?
Oh, y-yes! This is it!
I don't like to add to my debt.
But with this, I can secure another 30 million.
What's left is my bank account and hidden fortune.
Now, how far can we go?
This is getting really interesting!
Why do you go so far?
Look here.
I'm a bastard who finds entertainment when others are corrupted or fall from grace.
I've always been like this, even before I found out I'm physically hindered from becoming a magus.
However,
a bastard has dignity of being a bastard.
If you think it seems fun,
you need to properly and squarely bet until the ultimate end
even if you're betting your parents or your own self!
If you stay in a safe area without doing so,
that is no longer a bastard.
You demote yourself to simply being a cowardly chicken.
Now, we will resume from 240 million.
250 million.
260 million.
280 million!
300 million.
320 million.
330 million!
340 million.
350 million.
360 million!
370 million.
400 million!
410 million!
410 million. Going once!
420 million.
430 million!
460 million!
500 million!
Hold on a second!
We won't allow a second break.
There is something about Trisha Fellows' death
that I want out in the open.
Oh, what's the matter, Lord El-Melloi II?
Are you dissatisfied with my deduction?
The logic was full of holes,
but your deduction itself had no errors.
That is why...
I would like you to look at this first!
You know...
I needed it to resolve the situation.
I took some liberties to bring it out here.
Let's hear the great detective's deductions, then.
Then,
allow me to clear things up, starting with the serial murders from seven years ago.
In that case, all victims were beheaded, and their heads were missing.
Now, what do you think based on the situation?
That they are dead.
Huh?
Come on now, Waver!
If there's no head, of course they're all dead!
Then, what was the reason Trisha Fellows hid her head?
It was a dying message, right?
Yvette Lehmann gets a 3 out of 10.
She was a wielder of Mystic Eyes.
Th-Then, the perpetrator tried to take Trisha's Mystic Eyes from her?
But this train is the only way Mystic Eyes can be extracted from a human corpse.
No, the victims' heads were all taken.
They weren't necessarily dead.
"You are dead if your head has been taken away."
That is in itself an assumption!
Trisha's head, after being severed,
was still alive!
Yes. A talented magus can keep someone alive with just the head.
That way, he could freely use Mystic Eyes
without transplanting them.
You simply need the heads of the Mystic Eye wielders.
Master, are you saying that the case seven years ago
were crimes to seize and use Mystic Eyes at will?
That's my deduction.
Then,
why was Trisha killed?
She was investigating the case from seven years ago.
If the perpetrator obtained Mystic Eyes from every victim,
it should've been possible to obtain information about the Holy Grail War.
That's why he tried to contact Karabo and myself.
In other words, you aren't denying
that Karabo Frampton was the perpetrator for the case seven years ago, right?
Miss Adashino, are you familiar with this?
It's what Trisha Fellows hid inside the imaginary spell together with her head.
As vision is the oldest form of magecraft,
Mystic Eyes have a myriad of countermeasures.
For instance, using a lewd talisman to block line of sight of the witness.
If the power of vision is strong, it can even be reflected.
A reversal of Mystic Eyes.
I see. I had foolishly forgotten about that possibility.
You can manipulate Mystic Eyes that aren't being controlled.
The reason why you hid this was to prevent everyone from realizing that possibility.
Do you want to say that Karabo was being manipulated by Trisha?
That's a jump in logic.
I'm saying that the possibility of a third party intervening with Karabo's Mystic Eyes
is intentionally lacking from your deduction.
I see.
Indeed.
So, the perpetrator and mastermind are separate, huh?
So, what happens from there?
Trisha, in her Premonition, predicted that she would meet Karabo.
She boarded this train to gain the truth about seven years ago from him.
And then?
And that was her mistake.
She lost her life by a blade from the past that could not be prevented by Premonition.
Um, professor, are you saying that the true perpetrator manipulated Karabo
and committed this murder as well as the ones seven years ago?
There's just one person who can make that possible and also has a motive.
So, who is it?
Oh, that?
This is the answer.