No.
Not one person arrived at a place like this.
Why did you seek such a place?
Why didn't you let this go?
You'd known it was all a dream. Why didn't you acknowledge that it's a dream?
Answer me, Iskandar!
Hephaestion?
A dream?
Master!
He's fine.
He's gotten over the worst of it.
I'm so glad!
I see. Looks like he failed to die.
You have good skills, contrary to what I expected.
Is healing magic your forte?
My forte or not,
he taught me Electrical Magecraft several weeks ago.
Several weeks?
I've heard rumors about the El-Melloi Classroom, but...
A Servant attacked you?
The phenomenon of summoning a Heroic Spirit
with its original personality intact
can't possibly happen outside the Holy Grail War in Fuyuki.
"Invocation."
A spell enabling you to project Heroic Spirits and Divine Spirits
onto yourself, so that you can borrow their power.
Oh, Professor!
If you were to invoke the god of manga,
would you become good at drawing manga?
Hey, why does it have to be manga?
The author of the manga I bought recently at the used bookstore is dead,
and I want to read the continuation.
In principle, it's possible.
Harboring the soul of the deceased on yourself in an attempt to artificially revive that soul...
It's what you call "Sibyl's Magecraft."
Many sibyls who have high affinity to astral bodies
are unaware of their links to memories and consciousness of such bodies.
So, it's a divine possession just like Animalism.
Right.
Can't you materialize the Heroic Spirit or Divine Spirit
and let them go on a manga drawing spree?
I'll just say that it's not impossible theoretically,
but securing enough magical energy to support such a spell is unrealistic.
Now, about invocation in practice...
Let's look at the example of
Native American faith in Power Animals...
That was without a doubt a
Heroic Spirit who has materialized.
Such power can't be that of a magus.
That's all the more reason she has something to do with this.
If it was a Servant, there should be a Master who summoned her.
And perhaps she was the one who murdered Trisha.
Magical energy needs to be supplied to summoned Heroic Spirits...
Any other characteristics?
Hephaestion.
I am the primary confidante of the greatest King of Conquerors in history, Iskandar!
That's how she introduced herself.
A Heroic Spirit who was even dubbed "the other Iskandar"...
I see. It all clicks now.
You guys didn't come aboard this train to buy Mystic Eyes, did you?
A Lord who has no interest in the auction,
the King of Conquerors who once was his minion,
and the subject who attacked him.
Let's see. So, Iskandar's relic has been stolen from you.
That about sum it up?
So it is.
Just like Trisha said, this Lord is fixated on the King of Conquerors.
I see.
If it's a Heroic Spirit who is regarded in the same way as Iskandar,
you can summon her from the King of Conquerors' relic.
Does that also mean that her Master is aboard this train, as well?
That is quite likely.
But about Hephaestion, it's the opposite of normal.
Opposite? What is opposite?
Normally, Servants hide True Names when possible
because they expose their weaknesses and abilities.
Instead, they're usually called by the class that the Heroic Spirit is designated,
like "Saber" and "Lancer."
So, we know the True Name, but we don't know the class, huh?
What's the matter, Sir Rodin?
There's an anomaly in the train's path.
This is hard to believe, but someone meddled with the tracks.
This train is headed toward the Child of Ainnash.
Can we throttle?
The output won't go down.
I see.
Nothing less from my old haunt.
If the Premonition is only a prediction,
it can't see through incidents with nothing leading up to it.
However...
We have an announcement to all passengers.
I regret to inform you that this train has entered the Child of Ainnash.
Wha...
Ainnash?
You're kidding! The Forest of Dead Apostles?
We're sorry for the inconvenience until we resume course.
But we ask that each passenger secure their own safety in the meanwhile.
What's this forest?
I'd like to check outside!
Hold on!
Do you want to die? Look.
This forest is screwing up the leyline.
Let's do it!
O noble spirit materializing the great desires...
I see.
They're trying to burn off the forest that the rails are heading into.
But if something like that can have any effect...
Receive our guidance and show the flames of origin!
Even if they call it the "Forest of Dead Apostles,"
it's only a byproduct severed from the main body. This should—
They strike in reaction to attacks?
Where to?
My room.
I'll put up a bounded field and barricade myself in until the situation is resolved.
That can't be! We can combine forces to escape or something!
I don't even know who killed Trisha!
And doing something about this forest in a situation like that?
It would only create more corpses.
But—
Let me tell you this! I'm not your ally or anything like that!
I'll do it myself.
I'm sufficient by myself.
No.
It's better if I'm alone.
Miss Olga Marie...
Trisha properly taught me so that I could do things by myself.
More like, are you able to protect your mentor through all this?
Jean-Mario Spinella's Zombie Cooking!
Today, let's enjoy cooking whole roasted zombies together with Jean-Mario.
There we go.
And with that,
we are finished!
Whoa!
And the curtain falls on Zombie Cooking!
Cut!
That was great, Jean-Mario.
Thank you, Kairi!
Is this person really versed in the affairs of the Clock Tower?
Yeah. Let me introduce you, Luvia, to Jean-Mario Spinella.
He's an old acquaintance.
Nice to meet you, young lady. Anything regarding the media and gourmet is my area of expertise.
First off, how about a meal?
Delicious!
Lean dry-aged meat with a perfectly seasoned sauce!
Thank you so much.
I added a bit of soy sauce in the Madeira for the sauce.
Soy sauce is good and all, but can I get to the heart of the matter?
Go ahead.
Remember the case seven years ago where many headless corpses were found in London?
I remember.
No magus who meddles with the media would be ignorant of it.
A murder using the same tactic happened on the Mystic Eyes Collection Train.
I see.
Back then, there were seven victims.
They were all said to have been holders of Mystic Eyes.
But I don't recall such an incident being on the news.
The Clock Tower put on some pressure, and so did the Holy Church.
In the media, it was limited to one or two broadcasts on local stations,
and the tapes of those broadcasts have been seized by the Clock Tower.
Was the case ever resolved?
Surely, the case has been settled as a result of joint investigation with the Holy Church.
I'm sure of it because I got the info from a friend in Scotland Yard.
In any case...
What's wrong?
Well, is this case booming right now or something?
A girl from Astromancy wanted to hear about it just the other day.
Can we ask you what her name was?
Trisha Fellows.
It's as cold as Siberia outside.
I don't know how long we can last with the heating equipment on this train.
Will Master...
He seems fine for now, but...
Hey!
A-A person?
Well, I heard that Waver was here,
so I came by helicopter to watch,
but a forest suddenly spawned, and I got engulfed.
I thought I was going to die.
Well, that's...
Such an idiot...
Hasn't changed one bit.
Still an idiot as he's always been.
There surely are many easier ways of life for you.
Can I ask you one thing, Miss Gray?
Sure!
Who injured Waver this badly?
Who other than myself?
That's...
I understand that you are busy,
but we need to talk.
You need us to lend a hand to move this train?
Regretfully, we must now think about the possibility of canceling the auction.
If that happens, I can't extract these Mystic Eyes until the next auction.
And so, we want our little apprentice and Caules to help us out.
But how?
I have a bit of knowledge about this forest.
This location is a topic of conversation in the Holy Church, as well.
In the Holy Church?
Ainnash.
The forest is a thinking, preying organism, said to perhaps be a Reality Marble
controlled by a high-ranking Dead Apostle of the same name.
If we can find the main leylines,
and sink in a few guide markers from our end, we can activate them.
And by doing that, we should be able to move the train.
But most of the magi are barricading themselves in their compartments.
That snake lady from Policies refused, too!
She's so obstinate!
The more people we have, the better.
Can you help us out?
I'll do it!
Miss Gray...
Master will not last being exposed to this cold.
All right. Leave Professor to me.
Then, can I mingle with you guys?
I may look like this, but I'm a tuner of magic crests.
You can't be the Melvin Waynes!
The legendary tuner?
We stand a good chance with this many people.
My body feels warm.
The sounds are resonating with our magic circuits and activating them!
It feels so good!
I improved your magic circuits by about 20 percent.
It should be of some use, right?
Thank you so much.
But why?
I go all out in order to witness amusing things.
This is one.
I'll detect all the other leylines altogether!
We're counting on you!
Well, I'm feeling really good thanks to the tuning,
so leave it to me!
I'd like to find at least two more pressure points for the leylines. Let's hurry!
Okay!
Hey, Gray!
What's wrong, Add?
Bad, bad, bad! The bad thing is looking this way!
Run away this instant!
No way!
What's wrong, little apprentice?
I'm sorry. Please go ahead without me.
Wait, ahead of you?
Please! I'll make sure to catch up!
What should we do?
Understood.
That sounds amusing, though.
Oh, you noticed me?
Add...
Dammit, I thought things might end up like this.
It's unfortunate that the narrow-minded man is not here.
Why did you assault Master?
I said it was because I didn't like him.
Even then, you must have some other reason you lured him out there!
Then, you can get it out of me with that blade.
That's what I've always done.
Not my style.
You stand on the battleground not to fight, but to talk.
Then, why do you have that blade?
I...
I can't surrender to you!
I just want to speak as equals and have you return the relic!
I see. So, that's your resolution!
It seems that previous guidepost has marked us as intruders.
Leave it to me!
Ta-da!
Yvette's Processed Mystic Eyes,
Burning Flame Version!
Amazing!
But it won't last long!
Then, run for it!
The next response is from the right!
A large rock at one o'clock!
That one!
I thought warriors were extinct in this era!
But you have good potential.
Potential?
That's right.
Your glimmer is trying to cling onto life,
somewhere between life and death.
The pain that Master is going through has a lot more value than anything like this!
Then, you shall give it all you've got for your loyalty!
I think I'm at my limit soon!
Oh man!
We're sliding down!
Oh, jeez!
This is why we say the Holy Church is barbaric!
This feels like a roller coaster!
There, in the center of the vortex!
All right!
We got a response! The leyline is activating!
It really is strange. It's strange.
A spell right on these coordinates?
Not the floor or the ceiling,
but it was embedded in the relative coordinates from the train?
But if it's something like that,
someone like that despicable Lord would've long since found it.
It's reacting to my magic crest?
This spell is of the Fellows family that branched out from Animusphere.
That's right!
A dimensional pocket with an Imaginary attribute!
If so, the password should open it.
"Silly Little Marie, straighten yourself out."
What is this?
Strange! This is strange! What's going on here?
What's the meaning of this, Trisha?
Was someone watching?
Oh, I'm glad. You found it.
Nothing less from the heir of the Animusphere name.
Where's Miss Gray?
It can't be!
Wonderful! I didn't think you could cross swords with me this well!
Likely beyond the boundaries of ordinary men!
You're worthy of applause!
An avalanche?
It was simply a divided piece of a monster.
With the domination of the leyline taken away,
it's become unbearable quickly.
What's wrong? If you don't escape, you'll die, too.
If I let you escape here, Master will be hurt! That, if nothing else...
Add!
First Stage, Rescind Restraints!
I guess we have no other choice!
I won't let you get to him!
How well you bark!