No good.
Waletta's spirit is not responding to my calls.
There's no doubt about it.
Some kind of spell is interfering with the evocation.
Which means...
something caused by humans.
Seems that way.
Then, according to the rules of criminal investigations,
whoever gains the most by this death...
must be the one...
Wills Pelham Codrington.
Hold it! If our boy is the perp,
he didn't need to call a Lord all the way out to the crime scene!
He could've done so to create a witness.
No. The true perpetrator is someone else.
There's no doubt about it.
In the world of magi,
it doesn't matter who did it, or how.
You want to say you can only deduce the why, right?
That's why we can assume he's the only one with a motive.
Miss Adashino,
what you call Wills' motive is just speculation.
Yes.
Just like what you plea in defense, Lord El-Melloi II.
I've been entrusted with this case by Spiritual Evocation.
I'll continue with the investigation until the storm passes.
All right.
I would definitely like to hear
the deductions of our great detective.
Unbelievable. You're still going to continue?
You really live up to your rumors.
Rumors?
All sorts, yeah.
So, what are you gonna do now?
Our boy Wills is now confined by Adashino.
You thought of a countermove already, right?
I need you to help me, Shishigou Kairi.
I need the assistance of a Necromancer for this case.
I'd like advance payment.
I don't have much on me.
Just gimme one of those.
Thanks.
So, what is your end up to?
The execution of justice of course.
Policies does not deal with magecraft,
but only with politics.
Can't you give me a slightly better joke?
You like it, too, don't you?
Fun things like this...
I did say I'd help,
but I didn't think I'd have to help out gathering reference materials.
I-I'm sorry.
Is something wrong?
Yeah.
It just brought back some memories.
You like things of this nature?
Not me. Someone in the family liked them.
A child?
Yeah, I guess you could say that.
In Britain, they say that when children die,
their souls can't reach Heaven, and they become fairies.
But a Necromancer has nothing to do with fairies or Heaven.
That's enough storytelling.
Let's go back.
Oh, I'll take that!
It's fine.
I need the Lord to owe me a favor.
That's right.
I've never left my village before that,
so I'm surprised at so many things in London.
It must be rough being an apprentice.
But Master is very good to me.
That's a...
Black Dog.
A Fairy or an evil spirit that appears at crossroads.
Run! It's a bit too much to bear for you, missie.
Add!
H-Hey!
First Stage, rescind restraints!
You're amazing, missie.
That's a monster of a Mystic Code.
I didn't expect a Black Dog to appear within the Workshop.
We're within a strict bounded field.
There's no way it occurred naturally.
We can assume it was the true form of the lightning that killed Waletta and the others.
A Black Dog is also an incarnation of thunder.
The danger this Workshop holds is becoming more and more obvious.
There's something I want to ask before that.
About missie's Mystic Code.
What is that?
Do you need that information right now?
The Black Dog feared it.
It could be the key in figuring out the Dog's nature.
Gray?
That is King Arthur's spear. Rhongomyniad.
A spear? That scythe is one?
The scythe is a disguise.
Add and the scythe are simply Codes to seal away the spear.
Shut up! Respect me more!
A portrait of King Arthur created by a certain family...
That is what she is.
Wait, wait, wait!
King Arthur was a guy, right?
No, a woman. A girl of about Gray's age.
I've met her as a Heroic Spirit in the Holy Grail War. No doubt about it.
Holy Grail War?
The magecraft ritual...
where seven Heroic Spirits fight each other
for the omnipotent wish granter.
So, it's true that you were part of that battle.
I simply witnessed it.
I didn't fight at all.
But I see.
King Arthur, huh? That would convince me.
Here in Britain, an army of spirits appearing with wind and thunder...
is the Wild Hunt led by King Arthur.
Indeed.
If spirits of the deceased who couldn't go to Heaven or Hell are ghosts and fairies,
King Arthur is the king of ghosts and Fairies.
King Arthur was defeated, and left for Avalon.
That tale is based on a mythological journey to the underworld.
So, that's it!
I understand everything now.
And now, I can prove my hypothesis!
I'm commencing the ritual.
Wills, Shishigou, Reines...
Are you all ready?
I'm ready, but...
I don't think you can evoke those involved even if you change locations.
I'm not evoking.
This is the spell.
Elder brother, I can't assist with the ritual in my current condition.
I just need you to stand there. Trimmau, please support her.
As you wish.
We shall begin!
We hereby light the guiding flame!
Thou from yonder, pass through the white walls and see the guiding flame!
Thou art an iron hammer shattering deceit,
a ship crossing the blue seas,
a staircase to pass over the valleys!
I invite thee, child of celebration, wild child of fertility!
O eternal flame,
dispel the mist and bring forth a guest from yonder!
You are...
Just as I thought.
To think you would actually use magecraft of this nature...
Huh? You can speak?
It's not difficult
if you make Wills' Fairy Eyes harmonize with the element in Reines' Mystic Eyes.
Are you treating people like catalysts?
You're a catalyst!
I'm not simply treating you like one!
This Workshop was designed to draw out the powers of Mystic Eyes...
to utilize Wills' Fairy Eyes.
My Fairy Eyes?
It uses leylines to activate Mystic Eyes to draw out their power.
And that magical energy uses the dead as the cores to create artificial Fairies!
Isn't that so?
That is correct, son of man.
Just as I thought.
What does that mean, Master?
So, the perpetrator was Sir Trevor,
and the weapon was the Workshop itself.
I had known that since I entered this mansion.
So, the lightning strikes weren't accidents but premeditative murders?
That's right!
This Workshop in itself is a giant device for murder!
The Marbury Workshop calls down the Black Dog and kills humans.
The murders all took place on days where the alignment of the Moon and stars
heightened powers of the underworld and Earth.
Fifteen people in three years.
Those killed were transformed by the Workshop
using the Fairies' powers and Fairy Eyes into a new artificial Fairy, the Black Dog.
A dog that devours the souls of the dead, huh?
This Workshop was for Sir Trevor to control artificial Fairies to serve under him.
He must have not cared about how many would die for that cause.
In other words, that Fairy there and Wills' Fairy Eyes
are all like gears of this Workshop?
But why did Sir Trevor die?
It's not like he died because he lost control of the place.
I killed him.
You did?
That's right. That magus deceived me and disrupted our order.
Therefore, I punished him.
I see.
But that didn't stop the Workshop itself, and that's why you sought for help.
I had known that girl would die.
Power can't be stopped once in motion.
I had known about it, but I couldn't stop it.
You are...
I didn't want to make you sad.
That's all.
Oh, I see.
You didn't want to let go of the Workshop because she was here.
Am I correct?
How did you...
Your disdain of women is famous.
Those who can see Fairies are enchanted by Fairies.
That's what this is about, right?
That is a lovely, romantic relationship,
but can't you say that Wills' Fairy Eyes killed Waletta, then?
He was merely being used!
Would you put the knife used to commit a murder on trial?
The leyline is moving strangely!
This is...
Run!
We managed to escape!
What the...
They're running out of control!
Oh, crap!
What is it, Lord?
I underestimated the effect of the bounded field Adashino had put up!
As a result, it seems my ritual has activated the Workshop!
Sorry. I should've noticed that.
No, this would've happened sooner or later.
The dead call for the dead,
and the Black Dog will transform into the Wild Hunt! Look!
That's...
A gate to the world of Fairies!
Hey, it can't be that...
It's exactly that.
They're looking for more of their kind!
They'll add us to the queue of the dead.
I see.
What are you going to do?
It seems I'm at least partially responsible.
I will hold it in for a while. Please leave Miss Reines to me.
Understood.
Let's go!
This is my father's...
Not bad, Mr. Elite from Spiritual Evocation!
Hey, Lord,
can I invoice expenditures to the Clock Tower?
Send it to Policies!
Gotcha!
Dammit! How many people has this killed?
Seeing how many in the underground graveyard,
there must be quite a few deaths that weren't reported.
You had a hunch, didn't you?
Well, yeah!
We have no choice, Gray.
It's up to you.
Understood.
Hey, what's starting up?
We're going to use the Rhongomyniad.
Seriously?
Give us backup!
Gray.
Rave.
Crave.
Deprave.
I see, so, that...
...has been used.
Grave, me.
Grave for you.
Oh no!
They've realized that she's our ace in the hole!
Don't worry!
Do what you will!
Old Mystics.
Exterminate sweet mysteries.
All will return to the void.
Pseudo-Personality suspended.
Mana yield exceeds regulation.
Second stage, restraint rescinded.
Sacred lance, removing restraints!
The lance of King Arthur...
Surely, it can't exist in this era.
Rhongomyniad!
The Lance that Shines to the End of the World
The gate is not gone?
It was too late!
Sir Trevor's spell was perfect!
It's not enough to just eradicate the artificial Fairies!
We have no other choice.
What will you do?
I'll gouge Wills of his Mystic Eyes
and destroy the Workshop.
No, even that is useless.
Even if you did that, all that will happen is that the sealed spirits will run wild!
But who knows how many months it'd take to analyze and dismantle the spell?
There is a way.
A way to dismantle the spell.
I should've done this from the beginning.
I had my hunches all along, yet...
Wait, Wills!
If you do something like that...
I will not die.
I will go to the land...
where she, my father and Waletta are waiting for me.
Stop it!
The dead will draw you in!
Wills!
Thank you, Lord El-Melloi II...
for dismantling the mystery around me.
Farewell.
Wills!
Thank you for the hard work in solving the case.
I would like to give you a word of thanks.
I'll listen.
I found some amusing materials while taking care of the aftermath.
What kind of secret does
Marbury Workshop still hold now?
The origin of Wills' Mystic Eyes.
Origin?
You are born with Mystic Eyes...
No way!
Yes. The "Mystic Eyes Collection Train."
You know of it, right?
Just in rumors.
Rail Zeppelin, the phantom train that buys and sells Mystic Eyes.
It really existed?
It seems that Sir Trevor created Wills
to be the foundation for the Workshop from the beginning.
These are the materials concerning Rail Zeppelin, though just a copy.
Can it be that Policies were here all along to collect these materials?
Oh, what are you talking about?
You vixen! I shouldn't have dealt with you after all!
One word of advice for you, missie.
Never take your eyes off of that Lord.
From Master?
A guy captivated by the dead is rather troublesome.
The dead stay at the side of the living
and always drag them toward the past.
Even Servants in the Holy Grail War are no doubt still part of the dead.
Holy Grail War...
Oh, you are quite an avid student!
I don't know what he saw during the Holy Grail War.
Shut up!
If you're done with your affairs, hurry up and go back!
However, at the rate he's going, he will become roped into more trouble.
In the first place, your actions were excessive back in Adra, too!
He needs you, missie.
Well now, stay healthy!
Gray!
Yes!
We're going back to London, too!
Yes! Be there right away!