I see, this is quite the bounded field.
It looks impossible to brute force yourself past it.
I'd expect nothing less from something the Edelfelts own.
I'm honored to receive such compliments.
I mean, not even the El-Melloi Princess can find a way to escape from it.
From ancient times,
various myths and legends have stated that wealth springs from underground.
Graves and the underworld have another aspect of being storehouses for treasure.
Sir!
In other words, you should hide your treasured collection under the floor!
Like games, and those promissory notes in safes hidden in underground labyrinths!
And secrets adults hold?
But Professor, you have no need for such because you have me.
I'm always okay with personal lectures, or rather I want to be your mistress!
All right, you guys, shut up right now or get triple the homework. Take your pick.
Kings stockpiled immense fortunes in their graves
to continue their reign in the afterlife.
For instance, the pharaohs of Egypt...
Babylonia's King of Heroes...
Gilgamesh...
Sorry, I'll continue with the lecture.
From ancient times, it has been said wealth springs from underground.
Hold on, you've already covered that part.
Oh, is that so? Sorry. Let's see...
I don't know what he saw during the Holy Grail War.
However, at the rate he's going,
he will become roped into more trouble.
The Holy Grail War...
So...
what'd you want to talk about?
Um, well...
You're drawing this out.
There's something you want to ask, right?
And it's about your mentor,
my dear elder brother.
It's about the Holy Grail War.
Master supposedly was a part of this Holy Grail War in the past.
What happened to him there?
That's what I want to know.
So I see.
Now, I don't mind talking to you about it,
but it's rather dull if I told you for free.
Gaining information requires a suitable compensation.
Since you're here,
why don't you accompany me in my hobbies?
Understood.
This does look good on you just as I thought!
Th-That's not true! You can see my face, too!
It's fine. We're the only ones in the dressing room.
You promised me, right?
With over 150 years of tradition,
Carnac is one of London's biggest department stores.
As compensation, you agreed to come with me on my shopping trip.
But it's all been about me!
It's okay! It's okay!
You'll need winter clothes soon, right?
I will personally choose clothing for you.
Isn't this a bit too daring?
Oh no, a magus has to experience all things. Experience!
Yep! This suits you more than I imagined, too!
They do say that clothes make the woman!
Hold it, you guys!
What's all this commotion about?
M-Miss Luvia!
Why are you here?
Why, you ask?
I'm the owner of this establishment, Carnac.
So, this entire store belongs to Miss Luvia.
The original owner was Sir Davenant who was arrested in that incident the other day.
The magus...
So that's why the architecture is this strange.
It's magecraft designed to stimulate customers' eagerness to purchase.
I did change the interior decoration quite a bit to suit my aesthetics.
So that's why.
Isn't this a little over the top?
I adapted some of my Gem Magecraft here, too.
Since you're both here, I'll give a personal tour of the newly reborn Carnac.
Come on, you're being a bit pushy.
You guys are bored, aren't you?
It's not that often where all three of us coincidentally gather in one location.
I see. You're inviting us to a girls' party.
All right. You're okay, too, right, Gray?
Sure!
So, this is a girls' party.
I...
I'll do my best!
Perhaps, this is a bit too provocative?
I mean, Professor seems to still be a virgin.
Is something the matter?
Maybe it really is a bit over the top?
Oh, you want that?
Oh no, this is...
I know.
I'd ruin it for you if I were to buy that.
Well, I have a few things to take care of,
so please relax here in the owner's room.
Are you tired?
I was experiencing everything for the very first time,
so I was a bit overwhelmed.
London is very stimulating, isn't it?
Yes.
Back in my homeland,
there really was nothing there.
Now that Luvia has stepped out, it's the right time.
Let's chat about what you've been wanting to hear.
The Holy Grail War.
A magecraft battle in the Far East,
fighting over the omnipotent wish granter.
Seven magi and seven heroes famous through human history
serving them as Servants, fought each other.
What kind of Servant did Master fight alongside?
Iskandar.
Also known as Alexander the Great.
It's truly a ridiculous fairy tale.
The supposed King of Conquerors
who created one of the most prominent empires in human history...
The King of Conquerors, Iskandar...
He's quite established among the great Heroic Spirits.
That's probably why my incompetent elder brother
was able to survive through the Holy Grail War.
What exactly did Master see within that battle?
That's something even I don't know.
But a lad named Waver Velvet, who survived through the ordeal,
has chosen the path of suffering by inheriting the name "El-Melloi."
So, it was such an important experience for Master that it changed his way of life?
That's what it means.
But then, wanting to participate in another Holy Grail War...
My elder brother seems to be quite particular about that memory.
Memory...
A blackout?
Miss Reines?
You guys are fine, right?
What was that just now?
This is...
What in the world...
Nobody is here?
A bounded field of the magical sort.
One so extraordinary that my Mystic Eyes
show an excessive reaction to it.
Looks like this isn't one of your pranks, Luviagelita.
Of course it's not! I'll toss that line right back at you!
I-In any case,
we should get out of this building.
Trimmau.
Check what's beyond the door, but do it carefully.
Yes, Master.
Is it...
Just as I thought.
This is a type of alternate space.
It seems we've been severed from the real world.
I'm sure the other exits will behave the same way.
Does that mean we're trapped in here?
But why just the three of us...
Perhaps an assassination attempt on the next head of the El-Melloi,
a family that also has many enemies within the Clock Tower?
Come on now!
You, too, must have grudges for all the aggressive actions you've taken, right?
For now, let's think of a way to escape.
Can't we contact anyone outside?
No good.
No electromagnetic waves have succeeded connection for a while now.
That means we must get through all of this by ourselves.
Or do you think we should bet on sitting here and waiting for help?
Of course the answer to that is "no."
I'll make whoever planned such a ludicrous ordeal regret it!
It seems we're in agreement there.
Call blue, red, green...
for your queen!
No good after all.
This is getting rather annoying.
This reminds me of what happened at the Separation Castle.
Come to think of it,
Miss Luvia, you got trapped inside a bounded field back then, too.
I'd like to hear the details about that.
I reject that request!
And Gray, don't say things you don't need to! Understand?
Yes!
But we're getting nowhere.
It's impossible to open an escape route with magecraft we have on hand.
Back then, Master was with us.
If Master was here in a time like this...
That's it, Gray!
Indeed, if said El-Melloi II was here,
it would be his forte, his specialty to dismantle such a crisis.
What are you...
And fortunately, we know a little bit of how that man teaches. His logic, his tactics.
Well, do you mean we should try mimicking what Master might do?
Exactly.
It seems we can't figure out any other option.
Well now, Gray...
M-Me?
You're the one who knows how he does things best.
At times like this, what would the starting point for his logic be?
If it was Master...
It would be the whydunit.
That means the motive.
Why were just the three of us trapped in here?
That's not even worth considering.
There are plenty of reasons why someone would target us.
Um...
Unlike the two of you,
I'm not that important a person.
You're just a poor student
compared to these young ladies!
I don't think that's the case.
But if this was a plan targeting one of us,
it's unnatural to get all three of us together.
Besides, it's strange they just captured us and haven't made any other actions.
That's just it. Compared to how grand this bounded field is, it's somehow a sloppy job.
It's as if the perpetrator isn't thinking at all.
Um...
What if there was no perpetrator
from the beginning?
What do you mean by that?
Perhaps, it wasn't like someone targeted us and locked us up in here.
I see. So, not an incident but merely an accident.
You're suggesting that the magical structure
of this building ran out of control?
Are you saying there were faults in the interior decorating that I adjusted?
In the name of my family, I never used cheap spells that would do as such.
It's the reverse, "Owner."
It's not that there was anything lacking,
but there was just too much,
and it created an excessive reaction.
Can't you think of it that way?
What the...
Th-That just can't...
So, you have an idea...
about what I'm talking about?
Something wrong in this hall?
I said the building was enchanted with magecraft
stimulating customers' eagerness to purchase, right?
The key element for the spell is right here.
I see.
In magecraft, wealth springs from underground,
and that's why we're in the basement.
It's over there.
Is that Gem Magecraft?
Yeah, way too over the top.
It's just like getting carried away and putting way too many toppings on a parfait!
H-Hush, you!
In any case, if we can somehow deal with that...
This is...
So, the security system is also running out of control?
I can see that without you saying anything.
Can't you stop it somehow?
My systems are perfect!
There's no way outside intervention will be authorized!
All right, I get it.
Trim.
Yes?
Hold up.
This is my store.
I'll settle everything by myself.
Get down.
P-Pro wrestling?
Just look at that!
A graceful mannerism unleashes a
department store full of murderous techniques!
A Scandinavian human forklift!
Or you could call her
"Heracles revived in modern day"!
What the hell is that Flatt guy teaching Trim?
Catch-as-catch-can is a game for the ladies!
Amazing!
So, that's what every lady should know about!
Oh, don't go believing her, okay?
All we need to do now is to break this?
But are you fine with that? It must cost quite a bit.
It's inexpensive as the price for the lesson I learned.
At times, one must discard even things that are important in order to proceed.
Even things that are important...
Nothing less from the head of the Edelfelt family.
Well then, Trimmau?
Yes, Master.
Oh, brother...
That was quite an adventure.
Now, to celebrate our return...
How about we have another round of afternoon tea?
I must be careful about all the toppings I add on.
We were involved in quite the trouble today.
Yes, but somehow it ended up being fun.
However, there's something I don't understand.
If that was magecraft on a building running out of control,
what caused it to activate?
Oh, I can at least make a theory in the fashion of my elder brother.
Carnac was enchanted with magecraft to gather a fortune.
In other words, it was a spell that didn't allow fortune to escape.
Didn't allow an escape?
Can it be—
Right. We were seen as treasures to not be taken outside,
even if it meant putting up a bounded field.
But I can understand Miss Reines or Miss Luvia,
but I'm not that...
Come now, what are you talking about?
You have the most mystic of Mystics.
You carry one of the most prominent Noble Phantasms in human history!
Jeez. Having low self-esteem can be questionable, too, okay?
O-Okay.
Um...
So, this... He won't think this is strange or anything, will he?
Of course not.
I have returned, Master.
Yeah.
Seems like she took you around on quite a trip.
I'm sorry my little sister troubles you so much.
Oh no, not at all.
It was fun for me.
I see.
Master?
Oh, nothing.
Um...
I-If you'll excuse me...
Hold up!
Something...
...of utmost importance to me has been stolen!
A relic of a certain Heroic Spirit.
That would be...
You heard from Reines, didn't you?
The Heroic Spirit that I fought alongside in the Holy Grail War ten years ago...
The mantle of Iskandar.
The key for Master to reunite with said spirit...
All that's left inside the box that housed the relic was this letter.
"We hereby invite you to our banquet.
We request the pleasure of your company, so we hope that you will attend by all means.
The Mystic Eyes Collection Train,
Rail Zeppelin."
Rail Zeppelin?
Yeah.
It gathers any and every Mystic Eyes out there
and puts them on auction once a year.
A train full of supernatural beings.
Then, that's where...
Gray...
Will you head out to Rail Zeppelin...
together with me?