Wh-What do you think you're doing, snatching me from the street without so much as a by-your-leave?!
I've been a secret admirer of yours
for some time, my dear Waver Velvet.
And who in blazes are you supposed to be?
Reines El-Melloi Archisorte.
If I said I was the sister, by succession, of Kayneth El-Melloi Archibald,
participant in the Fourth Holy Grail War
and your former professor, would that ring a bell?
I'm his niece, if we're speaking strictly in terms of bloodlines.
So you brought me here for—
Perish the thought. I have no interest in vulgar things like revenge.
I merely wished to ask you a question
that's been on my mind for some time.
You were a participant in the ritual conducted in Fuyuki City
to summon an omnipotent,
wish-granting Grail,
and the Holy Grail War
to determine who would claim it, correct?
I was.
Where my brother lost both the War and his life, and brutally at that.
Yes. I met defeat as well.
Fortunately, my life was spared.
I wouldn't be so quick to call that fortunate, but let us move on.
Six months ago, you returned to England,
borrowed enough money to put you deeply in debt,
and purchased the right to operate the
El-Melloi Classroom my brother left behind.
So you see me as a thief who made off
with his mentor's legacy?
Not in the slightest! As a professor,
you're spoken of quite highly, you know.
However, I am quite curious about what motivated you to do all this.
I have a right to know.
Don't you think?
It's quite a long story.
You'd best shorten it.
I hear the human body can't endure
being suspended upside-down for long.
There's some debate as to the exact length of time required,
but after about three hours, the strain of circulating blood in reverse becomes too great,
and the heart simply stops beating.
I get the picture!
So this is Babylon.
The city built by Gilgamesh, first of kings,
and the place where Iskandar,
conqueror of all the world, met his end.
Damn it!
Curse you!
Move, you piece of scrap!
I've got to get to the doctor!
What's wrong?
I can't get this junk heap to start!
Damn it all!
He told me it was made in Japan!
Let me take a look.
Hey!
Don't worry. This was his city, once.
It's the least I can do.
Just as I thought. The spark plug's done for.
You only need it to get you
as far as the doctor's, right?
Yeah!
All right.
In that case...
For real?!
Will that do?
Y-Yeah!
It's just a temporary fix, mind.
Be sure to keep the engine running.
On your way to the doctor,
go buy a new spark plug!
I owe you one, tourist dude!
Hi there. You're clearly a magus.
I am.
That's what I thought.
These are...
Mystic Eyes of Binding!
I hail from the Clock Tower, myself.
The locals all know me as Barzan, the London boy.
I'm kind of a big deal around here.
Never heard of you. I'm just looking for somewhere to spend the night.
I didn't come here for a class reunion.
That's a combination of my Mystic Eyes and conditional magecraft I put on you.
Ain't that impressive, my dear underclassman?
I've seen better.
So you need a place for the night?
Come stay at mine.
Sound good?
Here you go! This here's the guest room.
It's no three-star hotel, but go on and make yourself comfortable.
Hey!
The body of a magus makes for excellent raw materials.
I'll be making full use of yours,
so don't wear it out too much.
As a living sacrifice, you mean?
So long, my little underclassman.
I'll send down some room service later.
Go to hell!
Couldn't cut it in London so you came here to strut around like a big shot, huh, you wanker?!
Shit!
Calm down, damn you!
The Mystic Eyes' effects are long spent!
Which means this is nothing more than a rudimentary barrier!
Would you please keep it down?
Put a bloody cork in it!
Y-You're...
Waver?
Waver Velvet! Is it really you?
Melvin?
The very same!
It's me! Your old school chum, Melvin Waynes!
I couldn't possibly be happier to see you!
Keep that away from me!
You never did stop the whole
"vomiting up blood without warning" thing, I see.
But what are you doing here?
A chap from school said it was the perfect place to seek my fortune,
so I got on a flight, and next thing I knew I was in here!
That must have been that Barzan scumbag.
I was so looking forward to meeting some lovely Arabian ladies,
but instead of my own 1,001 Nights, he just took my 30,000,000 dollars.
You're one sad bastard, Melvin.
What kind of way is that to talk to an old friend?
I don't recall us ever being friends in the first place!
Oh, so that's how it is?
After you borrowed all that money from me to go to Japan?
Well, yes...
Melvin! Wait up!
I heard that you'll pay any price for an interesting story.
That's right! If it's a really good tale,
no sum of my mum's money is too great!
Then pay for me to go to Japan!
Japan?
I'm going to turn this moldy old Clock Tower upside down!
So let's hear that interesting story you promised.
How did you find Japan?
You'd be able to lay your head in the
finest geisha's lap with the sum I gave you!
I'm sorry. It's not that kind of story.
I...
I entered that Holy Grail War, but...
I was completely useless.
Hold your horses. So the stories you were planning to tell me were of this Holy Grail War?
Yes.
But I suspect you already know.
There were rumors going around that
Professor Kayneth died like a dog over there.
So you didn't know that my uncle had died.
The Holy Grail War ended with no winner,
so it was hard to believe he'd still be alive.
Well, I suppose you had no way of knowing for sure.
His fiancée Sola-Ui was killed along with him, after all.
Their corpses were in a terrible state, I heard.
Barely anything was left to be salvaged of their magic crests.
Such a terrible waste.
Somebody murdered him.
It was the Saber-class Heroic Spirit, apparently.
Is this business about summoning great figures
from history and using them as familiars really true?
That's the Holy Grail War in a nutshell.
A battle to the death between legendary heroes.
Let's get out of here.
Waver?
I don't plan to stay here a second longer.
Knocking down the door by accelerating the natural aging of the hinges! What a fabulous idea!
There was no need to destroy it with brute strength.
When you discard your preconceptions,
you'll find all sorts of alternatives open up.
You've changed a lot.
You finally get your v-card stamped?
No, I did no—
Oh, do go on!
So, did you or didn't you?
That has no relevance to this story whatsoever!
Anyway, as we traversed deeper into the tunnels,
we reached his workshop.
What's this?
Oh, that. He's been feeding
the locals a bunch of lies
to con them into digging up
the ruins of Babylon for him.
It seems this could be where the tomb of Iskandar lies.
Just as well for us that the excavation is keeping them busy.
Time to make our escape.
What did you say?
I said we should get out of here.
Not that bit! Where did you say this is?
Like I said, it could be Iskandar's tomb.
I'm going to level this place.
What? I thought you said you needed to get out of here!
Not until I destroy it!
What fun! How I wish I could have had a ringside seat.
You've had adventures fit for a Hollywood hero!
Believe me, I'm no hero.
Do you really intend to do this?
If you don't like it, leave!
Quit the jokes! As I believe you know, I'm quite ill!
That's true.
Besides, I've got a ringside seat to one hell of a spectacle.
No way am I bowing out!
Then lend me a hand!
What?
That's all I have to do?
Damn! Another one?
It's so hard to find good help.
Consider yourself a sacrificial lamb.
Hold it!
Your actions are in violation of Clock Tower law against revealing the secrets of magecraft.
I can't let this pass!
Well, well, what have we here?
You're even duller than I thought.
You wriggle out of the trap and come running
to the hunter to be caught again?
By my Mystic Eyes!
Well, this suits me just fine.
Your magic circuits are thoroughly third-rate,
but I imagine they'll be adequate kindling for my atelier.
I'll be sure not to waste a single one.
Third-rate? Well, excuse me.
But then, that makes two of us,
doesn't it, my dear senior?
The Mystic Eyes I possess are invulnerable.
With those, and the relics of Iskandar soon to be within my grasp,
the Clock Tower itself will quiver before me!
Let me guess. You want to get even with the Clock Tower for ignoring your talent, right?
What?!
I knew it.
I've seen all these spells before.
But London and Babylon are nothing alike. Everything from the leylines on up is different.
You're in way over your head.
You bastard! What could you possibly understand about my magecraft?
Oh, I understand!
I know what it's really like when magi fight one another to the death!
That'll do it!
The terror, and the agony—
of which I'll be sure to teach you!
What have you done?
Oh, not much. I merely disrupted the leylines,
awakening the evil spirits that sleep here.
Your repertoire is but a collection of magic tricks—
a pale imitation of what the Lords can accomplish.
Overlook the slightest flaw, and this is the result.
I still have my Mystic Eyes!
In a magus-to-magus fight—
You witless clod!
When did I ever say a magus had to defeat another magus in battle to win?
What?!
What's eatin' you, Waver?
I'm sorry.
This is all I have to pay you back with.
I have none of the amusing stories I promised you, either.
I'm truly a powerless fool, but...
There's still something I want to do,
no matter what it takes.
So—
So?
Please lend me more money!
I want to buy back the El-Melloi Classroom that was lost along with my mentor.
Whatever for?
I can't stop thinking about it.
I really am...
responsible for his death.
I can't offer any collateral or guarantee.
But I'm begging you!
Sounds good to me!
With no collateral or guarantee, there's only one thing that would move me to lend you the money.
Name it.
Our friendship!
We're going to be the best of friends, Waver!
What are you saying?!
Doesn't this strike you as slightly odd?
Nothing odd about it!
I feel tremendously moved by your words!
So the money is yours!
Take as long as you need to repay it.
We're best friends, after all!
I'm begging you! Not down my shirt!
And there you have it.
I see.
And in the three years since, you secured the continued operation of the El-Melloi Classroom.
Not only that, but its success.
Spare me the sarcasm, would you?
You know as well as I do that I'm barely scraping by in maintaining it.
Leaving the particulars aside, the fact remains that you've allowed the El-Melloi Classroom to survive,
even surrounded on all sides by those
opportunistic Clock Tower goblins.
What you've accomplished
is nothing short of a miracle.
Which brings us back to my first question.
Do tell me, Waver Velvet.
What could have possibly
moved you so deeply
that you'd devote such effort to keeping that classroom going?
The one who killed your uncle, Lord El-Melloi,
and my mentor, Kayneth, was me.
He died because of my own
reckless and thoughtless acts.
My relationship with my master was far from amicable.
Nor did he hold me in high esteem.
But I can't deny that his class
shaped me into the magus I am.
I cannot deprive its future students of the opportunities it gave me
when I was the one seated in that lecture hall.
Oh, do excuse me!
I wasn't expecting such integrity from the likes of you! You've caught me off guard.
You do have a point, though. If you hadn't stolen that relic of Iskandar from him,
perhaps my elder brother
would have lived a touch longer.
That's right.
I couldn't use it to its full potential.
I wasn't fit to master the King of Conquerors.
I acknowledge the wrong I've done.
I only beg you to spare my life.
Oh ho?
Isn't this where you say something like,
"If this is not enough, then take my life also"?
There are things I still must accomplish.
In the name of my king.
Very well! As long as I have you here,
I may as well exploit your guilt
to make as many demands as I please.
The El-Melloi faction is rather deep in debt at the moment.
The money we owe would be enough to fund a Hollywood blockbuster.
So you intend to pass that debt on to me?
Of course.
Answering to our creditors is just one of the responsibilities that comes with the name.
Very well.
Are you serious?!
Do you think I'd take on a crushing debt as a joke?
I-In that case, the second condition!
What now?
I trust you've heard that my elder brother's magic crest—
the original magic crest of the El-Melloi line—
was nearly lost. We barely recovered a tenth of it.
I had. The essence of who he was as a magus was almost completely destroyed.
Even if our house Tuner worked at it day and night,
it would take at least three more generations to restore.
At this rate, our line is done for.
Understood. I'll take care of it somehow.
What is it?
Are you quite sure? Aren't you agreeing
to these terms with far too little resistance?
Did you come back from the Holy Grail War
with worms in your brain?
My gray matter is perfectly sound!
I said I'd assume responsibility, and I mean it!
It seems you do.
Then let's get to the heart of the matter.
You know what the title of Lord entails.
The highest rank a magus can obtain, and a seat on the council ruling the Mage's Association.
Everyone knows.
Yes. To the El-Melloi faction, retaining the position of Lord is absolutely necessary.
Without the power it grants to expel another Lord,
you'll swiftly find yourself outside the Clock Tower's inner circle.
I've been chosen as the head
of the family for the time being,
but I'm obviously too young to take on the title.
So I'd like you to keep the seat of Lord warm for me until I come of age.
I don't mind, but what exactly would you have me do?
Until I'm of age, you are to undertake
all work that the position of Lord entails.
Wait a minute! You mean—
I certainly do!
Playing diplomatic chess with the other Lords is sure to be a terrible bore, but I'll be counting on you,
the new Lord El-Melloi.
Or perhaps I should call you...
my dearly beloved
elder brother?
I'm to become my master Kayneth's successor?
I have one condition of my own.
What is it?
Please add "II" to "Lord El-Melloi."
My master is the only one worthy of the original.
The name is too heavy a burden for me to bear.
And here I was certain you despised my brother.
Personally, I'm not fond of him, even now.
But as a magus, I deeply respect him.
And most of all,
I have someone I must follow after!
That's right.
Even though the Holy Grail War is over,
as absurd as it is, life goes on.
So as long as I draw breath,
I must struggle to survive.
Until the day I reach the place you longed to see,
the furthest ocean!
Master! You've returned!
Yes.
The fallout from the Izelma business is finally over.
That is gladdening to hear.
You have a visitor waiting.
That can only be them.
Welcome home, my very best friend!
More trouble for me to deal with, I take it?
Of course, dear brother.
I have a case for you that will bring you
one step closer to paying off your debt.
I guarantee it'll be worth your while!
Let's hear it.
What sort of a case is it?
A supremely difficult one, of course.
More than fit for Lord El-Melloi II.