the Cat
All things in creation correspond.
Our own physical selves are each a tiny cosmos,
and we constitute a tiny piece of a corresponding greater cosmos.
In the quest to see beyond our realm,
the first tool humans took up was the mirror.
The image reflected in a mirror is false,
but the mirror gives you a glimpse into a world that corresponds with your true selves.
This is why human societies across the world have long venerated mirrors as avatars of the divine.
Whoo! Tell 'em, Professor Great Big Ben London Star!
It's Lord El-Melloi II. At least put some thought into a nickname.
It's fine! It corresponds with his true self plenty well.
Flatt Escardos.
Yes!
What is popular nomenclature for the act of renaming a target
without their knowledge or approval to exert an influence on their nature?
That would be a curse, sir!
Denouncing the god worshiped by a rival nation as a demon
or damaging a politician's credibility by referring to him
with an insulting nickname, would be two examples!
And if you would, Svin Glascheit,
please explain to the class how the hogwash that left
Mr. Escardos' lips relates to the concept of correlation.
Yes, sir.
Flatt's penchant for making up stupid nicknames for you
is an attempt to elevate your status to a greater level through positive correlation, sir.
However, the level of corresponding greatness is constrained
by Flatt's own woefully lacking mental capabilities.
Hey!
Precisely. And as a result,
my true nature remains unchanged.
A shadow reflected in a mirror may correspond with the true nature of its projection,
but it will forever fall short of its original.
In short, the interference of a shadow can make it possible for a target's true nature to be overwritten.
This is the very essence of a curse.
Thus,
we may think of magecraft as the sole technology through which our world,
a mere shadow of the Root, can be altered.
Goodness, what a masterful lecture. Succinct and easily grasped.
Well done, Lord El-Melloi II.
Thank you.
Truly, it was in every respect rudimentary.
It's disgraceful how we permit those ignorant of such fundamental concepts to call themselves magi.
Well, that's what comes of Modern Magecraft Theory
opening its doors to all seekers of knowledge.
It's beyond me why it's considered necessary, mind.
I, for one, found it quite impressive.
Professor Great Big Ben London Star,
is it?
My distinguished colleagues.
As you well know, I am a very busy man.
If you came to chat, kindly save it for the next faculty tea.
How many years does this make it
since you took over the El-Melloi Classroom after the former Lord's untimely death,
Waver Velvet?
This year will make ten.
Yes, that's right,
and ten years as well since my younger sister Sola-Ui
and her betrothed—Kayneth, your master—
met their deaths in the Fourth Holy Grail War.
How busy you've been, besmirching our institution with a circus of hooligans
and herding them into the
Modern Magecraft Theory Department.
What a splendid little fiefdom you've built from a subject that only existed on paper.
You flatter me.
I feel scarcely worthy of such high praise.
However, and it truly pains me to say this,
there are those among us who have voiced their concerns
about the course you are charting with your work.
You are Lord only until Lady Reines comes of age.
A simple substitute, nothing more than a fake.
I am well aware of my position.
I don't doubt that. We all know you to be a sensible man.
I must be going now, dear brother.
Do give my regards to your sweet little apprentice.
Welcome back, Master.
Back again, you mangy beast?
I'm sorry. It was I who fed him.
You're not at fault, Gray.
Hey! What do you think you're doing with your filthy paws on my sofa?
Get down this instant, you brainless moggy!
You bloody—
M-Master!
Now that you're back...
Leave it 'til I've had my cigar, would you?
Yes, sir.
Worthless bastards, the lot of them.
Beg your pardon?
Those fossils on the faculty, trying to badger me into declaring some clear allegiance.
Allegiance, sir?
Every Clock Tower magus is the same.
Constantly at all the others' throats, scrapping for power.
Our Department is a pawn to them, and they're eager to know whose side of the board it's on.
They're trying to force me to show my hand.
Will you be taking up arms against someone, Master?
Shit!
Excuse me.
I'm but the acting Lord.
In my position, I lack the power
to go toe to toe with the likes of them.
If I had the free time to waste hatching conspiracies,
I'd much rather devote it to my own research.
Master...
Unlike that pack of wizened bloody goblins!
Curse them all! Any magus so blind to the spirit of inquiry can fall straight into the bowels of hell!
By the by, Master,
Professor Willes from Spiritual Evocation says he really needs those reports from you.
Why the blazes didn't you tell me that sooner?
I'm terribly sorry. You said for me to leave it 'til you'd had your cigar, so...
Then the fault is mine.
Let's get going, Lady.
Ah, Milady Gray... your scent is just as ravishingly graceful, yet just as deliciously cool as ever today!
Don't you agree, Flatt?
I can almost see your tail start wagging
whenever you and Gray cross paths, Le Chien.
If you ask me, our Professor's the most adorable of the pair.
That's like comparing the fragrance of a fine perfume to the smell of a grilling steak. Practically pointless.
Which one's the steak here?
Hold it, Flatt!
Huh?
...I smell the Professor.
A-Are you all right, Master?
Get ahold of yourself! It's only a flesh wound!
They got me. Hit me head-on with a counter-curse.
Pardon?
You heard me curse them, didn't you?
Curse them all! Any magus so blind to the spirit of inquiry can fall straight into the bowels of hell!
Paltry name-calling though it might have been,
these Clock Tower ghouls would never pass up a chance to direct a curse back at its caster.
Fucking pissants. This overcoat was brand new.
I can dust it off for you later.
See that you do.
I do apologize, but I have somewhere to be. Clean up this—
Master!
You all right there, o venerable Professor Absolute Territory Magician?
I'm just fine! I'd be even better if you'd quit it with the stupid nicknames!
Just a term of my admiration, sir!
That makes it so much worse!
You'd think he'd have liked that one.
He got fourth on that "Professors that should lose the pants" poll, after all.
The worst part of this is that you're utterly serious.
Bleeding hell!
Oh, that's swelling something fierce.
Don't touch it, you miserable malkin!
Get me the anodyne herbs from that shelf over there, would you?
Yes, sir!
The Clock Tower's positively lousy with Lords,
but I daresay this is the only one hopping around tenderfooted
after his own mudslinging backfired!
Add!
No more of that.
For crying out loud.
I consider myself lucky that I only grazed an automatic defense mechanism.
That's what happened, then?
Think of it like tripping an alarm system.
It's most likely none of them even consciously realized I'd cursed them.
Cheeky devil! Get back here—
Master!
With buffoonery like this, who needs the circus?
Are you quite all right?
Ugh...
Quite important to you, weren't they?
Yes.
I spent my first pay packet from the Clock Tower on those shoes.
I'll get them polished for you.
Might not be able to get all the scuffs out, but...
Thank you, Gray.
Oh, Master, I've brought the herbs for you—
That cat.
I need to research what magecraft I can use to fix that cat's wagon.
There has to be a useful spell in here somewhere.
This is only my advice, Master, but I think you'd better not.
Were you up all last night?
Not all night. I fell asleep in the middle of a tome of sacred treasties of the tenth century.
Yes, sir. I saw that when I came in to wake you and toweled off your face.
I have no lectures today or tomorrow.
What does it matter?
It can't be—
This is too horrible.
What do you think you're doing
getting run over out here, you fool?
If you're a stray, then act like one.
Spare a thought for the trouble you'd cause for us humans if you die.
Master!
You could have at least had the good grace to have your accident in front of me.
Rumor has it Lord El-Melloi II shut himself into his chambers cradling some stray cat.
Care to confirm that?
You heard right. Why should a first-rate instructor like you concern himself with what the rumors say?
If what he's dabbling in needs a living sacrifice, a black cat is a laughably obvious choice.
Quite the contrary. If I know my brother,
he's taken the cat in purely out of sympathy.
What? Sympathy?
A magus, never mind a Lord,
indulging in such menial sentimentality?
That's a poor joke.
None of us magi are what you could call "normal".
If you look at it that way, there's none whose conduct more befits the name of a magus than him.
Master.
Won't you please have something to eat?
Won't be necessary.
I want to see this through first.
Do change your clothes then, at least.
Yours are still wet, and the stains must be setting in something frightful.
No need.
It's all right.
Master!
Those nights without sleep are catching up to me.
I worry your sentimentality will be the death of you sometimes, Master.
There's not so much difference
between those that walk upon the earth
and those what sleep within it, is there?
Is that how you see this world?
If there is any difference,
it's only with those that ought to be asleep but walk the earth instead.
It's beyond my power to understand.
It's all right if you don't.
This is nothing more than a trick of the mind.
If you seek the path of magecraft,
you haven't time to be tripped up by such trivial diversions as this.
Were you to ask any student,
I'm sure that's what they'd say.
If I were a first-rate magus, it would have been a trivial matter to heal those wounds.
Time and again, I'm too late and too powerless to make a difference.
Is that all I am?
Not in the slightest!
You're the reason I'm here, Master!
Gray. I don't wish...
to see that face of yours.
Sorry.
Don't be.
To have you detest this face of mine
makes me very happy.
I see.
What is it, Gray?
Nothing. I almost thought I could hear it still—
Stop that. There's no need for you to get bogged down in your master's sentimentality too.
No! I'm sure it's the cat!
I hear its cries!
A shadow.
So that's it.
A corresponding shadow!
My word...
Send for Svin and Flatt.
Shade that passes across the surface of water.
Dawn that rips aside the veil.
Tracks of amber that cross between stars.
Return here from the twilight, and blow breath into lead!
So this is the person who placed the curse on you, Professor?
To be precise, the car is the one that did it.
The culprit ran down the cat
after first binding it with a curse that would transfer its agony to me.
So in short, since the cat has a connection to you,
a mortal injury to the cat could kill you as well?
Precisely.
The car and its wheels symbolize the cycle of fate, constantly turning.
With the application of magecraft,
the culprit transferred the curse to my shadow.
So the culprit did this to the cat intentionally in order to kill you, Master.
But they miscalculated.
They never accounted for the depth of Gray's ties to the realm of death.
If Gray hadn't picked up on the cat's presence when she did,
I'd be in much worse shape.
I 'spose that's the one thing she's got going for her!
Add!
Then if the curse is possessing a shadow,
the reflection of that shadow in the mirror will show you its true nature!
Exactly.
Can you track it by scent, Svin?
Of course, sir. But that said,
wouldn't it be easiest to settle this by countercursing the culprit?
If I did that, I'd never find out who did this to me!
These Clock Tower folk certainly do pay well.
And no sign of a countercurse on the way, either.
I think it's high time I had myself a vacation in Monaco.
Spoke too soon.
That's our trusty ol' Le Chien!
Don't talk about me like some old bloodhound!
I've got to say though, the methods this guy used are incredibly reckless.
Now that the curse is cycling, it's not just affecting the Professor, it's running its course through him too.
Do you think I ought to tell him that in ten years time he'll be suffering gout, diabetes, or worse?
You can tell the bastard whatever you like after we catch him.
If I don't hurry up and get this sorted,
the curse will stop my heart.
Shit! Why won't you just die?
I can take care of this.
Just let us handle it.
This is for what you did to Milady Gray's cat!
Quit yapping and go!
Palladia Mors!
What the blazes?
Is that fortification?
No! It's bestial magecraft!
Game Select!
What a relief that you were able to apprehend the person behind this.
That man was merely the perpetrator.
His memories were more than likely altered.
In Reines' opinion, he didn't even know whose orders he was acting on.
Trying to solve the mystery of who really did it, and how,
is pointless when the culprit is a magus.
But the whydunit remains.
It's not hard to imagine why
someone would want me dead.
I'm a Lord, after all.
The cat was just collateral damage.
Still, I think that in doing this, you saved the cat.
Any feeling of satisfaction that saving something might give you is just another trick of the mind.
Helping others won't improve your own lot in life.
Nor will you ever know for certain if the help you gave them did any good in the long run.
Even so...
Even so, Master,
you saved me. And that's for certain.
And you saved the cat as well. That's what I believe.
What lies within our reach is a mere conglomeration of facts.
The one truth lies beyond our grasp.
Misconceptions, misunderstandings, mismatches and misapprehensions...
What an utterly foolish cycle of repetitions this world we live in is.
Little more than a shadow in a mirror.
Looking at it that way,
the battles I fought at your side were far simpler.
But now...
this place
is my battlefield.
Yes?
Very well.
Adashino from Policies wants a word with me again.
For pity's sake.
Will you be going out, sir?
Yes.
Looks like yet another nuisance needs my attention, Lady.