Wake up.
What is it?
Wake up, Waver Velvet!
Kayneth...
Professor!
So, are my lectures too ridiculous for you to listen to?
That's not exactly the case.
Then, answer me this!
Why do you seek to enter the Fifth Holy Grail War?
What do you seek with the relic you stole from me in hand,
and what do you desire?
I...
want to see him one more time!
A fool.
Servants are nothing more than familiars.
Next time they materialize, someone like you won't be remembered at all.
Even then... Even then, I want to prove to him...
that I was the one who was inferior.
That he...
Rider was the hero who should've been victorious!
Do you still think that way?
The Relic has been seized.
Hephaestion, who materialized, denied you as a subject of the King of Conquerors.
Even then, you say you'll still fight?
Of course!
Answer me once more.
What do you think victory is for a magus?
Being rid of all stereotypes and simply arriving at the final destination.
Then, what is your final destination?
Answer me, Lord El-Melloi II!
I will answer you, my mentor!
What I need to seek right now...
Why...
did you save me?
You were a warrior.
Warriors should die on battlefields whenever possible.
So, you'll kill if it comes to battle again.
That's right.
You are somehow similar to me.
I can tell when I look at that weapon.
That must be a replica of a
Noble Phantasm of some great hero.
And you, the wielder, also are.
A living incarnation of a distant ideal.
A counterfeit created for show.
Humans never change no matter what era.
However, though counterfeit,
you fight with your own desires.
You and I...
are the same.
My desires...
I don't know.
You can't fight like that without any desires for yourself.
My current desire is...
with Master...
But...
I see. You despise that narrow-minded scholar to come out into the battlefield that much.
Indeed. He will die if he enters a Holy Grail War.
He's not of a caliber to be victorious.
But that is what he desires!
I want to grant him that wish!
Loyalty and glory sometimes are contradictory.
But if you can't overcome that contradiction, both Master and Servant will perish.
Master and Servant...
A king is like the Sun.
Its heat burns away anything that gets near.
But subjects can't survive without the Sun.
For you, was Iskandar, King of Conquerors,
someone of that nature?
Yes.
There will be no other king like that.
Even if he falls to illness,
he said he was going to go further and see the Sea at the End of the World.
A grand king drove us forward!
How heated all of his words were...
How much they glimmered...
I was his primary confidante.
That's something I won't let anyone deny.
But why were you...
Why were you alone reprimanding Iskandar for his actions?
Miss Hephaestion?
What did you see?
Answer me! What did you see?
In a dream,
you were asking,
"Is this what you desired?"
"Why didn't you let this go?"
You said, "Answer me, Iskandar!"
Oh, I should've known.
You're a Sibyl. It seems you're especially versed in spiritual possession.
Looks like it stopped snowing.
When you can move again, you can leave here.
Though I don't know if you can catch up to that train.
I'm Mary Lil Fargo.
Can you talk to us about Trisha Fellows?
She's an old friend of mine.
So, she has passed away. I still can't believe it.
She was investigating a serial murder that happened seven years ago.
Have you heard anything about why she did so?
Olga Marie was abandoned.
That's what Trisha said.
Olga Marie is, um...
She's the daughter of Lord Animusphere!
It was about a month ago. The last day that I met her...
Seven years ago, Lord Animusphere was researching about the Holy Grail War.
The Holy Grail War?
Yes. It was right around when the serial murders were happening.
The Lord gained information about the Holy Grail War from somewhere.
But it's a very minor magecraft ritual in the Far East, isn't it?
Why would you look into it after all this time?
Since doing research about the Holy Grail War,
after a while, the Lord stopped showing interest in Olga Marie.
But a magus not leaving anything for his child can't be...
That Greater Grail was distorted,
and no matter what you do, it can't grant the family's wish.
That's what the Lord said.
But what does that have to do with him abandoning his daughter?
That's what I want to know.
What did the Lord find out seven years ago?
How is it related to the serial murder case?
And why did he abandon Olga Marie?
Trisha was doing research on the Holy Grail War,
and she boarded the Mystic Eyes Collection Train.
The victims of the serial murders,
including Trisha herself, were wielders of Mystic Eyes. Anything else?
A man without a heart.
What's that about?
Someone with a nickname like that
was doing research on the Holy Grail War
seven years ago by request from Lord Animusphere.
That's what she said.
Thank you.
This was of great help to us.
Nothing less from the Rail Zeppelin!
If it can locate a leyline, not even the Child of Ainnash will be an obstacle!
Is this a time to be celebrating?
I really do feel sorry about Gray!
But you know, she seems like she can take a few hits!
Enough with the excuses.
That's...
That hurts! It's cold!
I'm being shaven, planed, grated!
Wait, ouch, pain, ouch, pain,
I'm shaven, planed, grated, pain!
Open the door please!
And there we go!
Made it in time!
I'm so glad!
Oh, this is so amusing!
It definitely was worth crashing a helicopter for!
Mr. Caules, how is Master doing?
He's fine.
His condition stabilized soon after leaving that forest.
I see.
What, weak in the knees?
And harsh treatment aside, you didn't have to ride on the shield!
Enough already!
You should be more mannered in how you treat a box—
Gray! Stop! Hey! Stop! Gray! Hey!
Hey, what's wrong, Missie?
You suddenly have a sour look on your face.
A man without a heart.
I've heard rumors of a dangerous magus who once had his heart stolen by a Fairy.
By a Fairy?
If he's the person I know of, he has a younger sister-in-law.
And she's currently aboard that train.
Hey, that can't be!
No way!
I'm having everyone gather up in the lobby car.
Since the usual individual is still sleeping slovenly,
I will play detective for now.
What in the world is the reason you want all of us?
There's something I'd like to suggest from the standpoint of the Policies division.
Right, it's about the perpetrator of this case.
Oh yeah, Great Detective!
There was a serial murder case that used the same method seven years ago.
Pardon me, but I don't recollect any cases of that nature.
We at Policies had controlled information about it.
Wow, you'd actually admit that?
However, we weren't the only ones who meddled in this.
The Holy Church had also intervened.
The investigator in charge at the time was you, Karabo Frampton, right?
Correct.
Come on now! If you knew about it, you could say so!
That goes against my duties of confidentiality. Naturally.
I see.
Even with Mr. Karabo's Past Vision,
the crime scene couldn't be viewed.
Even with Miss Trisha's Premonition, she couldn't protect her own self.
I see.
So, the instant of the crime couldn't be viewed either from the past or the future.
That would leave us with one answer, plain and simple.
That location wasn't the scene of the crime.
I see! I get it! But of course!
As I'd expect from a Mystic Eyes specialist...
Past Vision and Premonition only transcend over the temporal axis.
If so, if you're not at the scene of the crime,
you can't see visions no matter how hard you try.
The crime scene wasn't that room?
Then, who are you saying murdered Miss Trisha?
Now, I'll have one witness enter the stage.
What is the meaning of this?
Her head was hidden using Imaginary Numbers Magecraft.
I presume that Trisha Fellows herself had sealed it away.
She sealed away her own head?
She likely realized she was going to die by beheading thanks to her Premonition.
She'd created an Imaginary pocket in advance to where the head would likely fall.
And this is the important part.
Inside a spell of Imaginary Numbers Magecraft,
time stands still.
Therefore, her head at the time of retrieval was still alive.
It was still alive?
With the final breath left in her throat, she uttered just one word.
What do you think was the word she left behind?
"Karabo."
Karabo Frampton,
your Mystic Eyes are those of Observation of Past Vision, correct?
What is Observation of Past Vision?
They're Mystic Eyes that can see a commonplace past.
You can perceive a past that's already been settled.
Even if you can see the past, you can't commit a murder, right?
Well, right.
Among powerful Mystic Eyes,
there are those who can bring the visions into the world as truth.
For instance, "The Mystic Eyes of Death Perception."
The legendary?
But those are Rainbow-class or Jewel-class!
Of course, this is only if the rumors are true.
But your Mystic Eyes are rather close to that, aren't they, Father Karabo?
I will record a slash like this and put it aside.
Then, if the wielder of the Mystic Eyes had observed it,
the target will be severed in the exact manner of the recorded slash.
I see.
So, didn't you do it?
Didn't you do it, Karabo Frampton?
You're saying I did it?
A train following the rails worked in your favor.
You just took a slice of empty air in the lobby car leading the way.
It'd be easy to see what location the chair would be with your Past Vision.
Because when her corpse was found,
the train had stopped in the woods, and you were outside.
You simply needed to peek into the window from the outside.
Then, dragged into the past you observed,
empty air would be torn apart once again...
right along with Trisha Fellows' head.
Wait? Does that mean the serial murder from seven years ago was also like this?
I can't think there would be anyone else with Mystic Eyes like that!
And that individual was involved in the investigation, huh?
Hold on, I...
I won't conclude that you're the perpetrator,
but this gives enough reason to take certain measures against you.
Wait a minute!
Oh?
Are you finally awake, Lord El-Melloi II?
Waver!
I didn't think you'd be here, as well, Melvin.
Oh! It's only natural for me to rush over when my best friend's in peril!
Just mind your own business.
Miss Adashino...
I have several doubts on your deduction.
You're already going to let me in on your marvelous detective work?
The deduction you just mentioned is lacking the element of motive to begin with.
Whydunit, your favorite?
Correct. There is no crime without motive.
If you really need a reason,
how about envisioning you and the bloodthirsty killer
as one and the same with Mystic Eyes of Past Vision?
What?
As he kept observing the murders seven years ago,
the sense of self and the killer melded together.
Wouldn't that be possible if he no longer can control his Mystic Eyes?
Are you seriously saying that?
Would it be okay if I was serious?
There isn't much of a difference between serious and nonsensical.
After all, we are magi.
So, that's your scenario.
But does Father Karabo's Mystic Eyes
really have that kind of power?
What do you mean by that?
Who proved that his Mystic Eyes could bring forth a recorded vision of the past?
Are you saying that is nothing more than my deduction?
It's not even worth calling it a presumption or even circumstantial evidence.
To be blunt, it's just a delusion.
Are you going to prosecute him based on something like that?
You don't need to worry about that at all.
All we need to do is to have the Mystic Eyes
appraised by Rail Zeppelin.
Yes. It would be possible with those Mystic Eyes.
Indeed, it can project a slash lost in the past back into the present.
Everyone, this is the deputy manager of this train.
It is now the appointed time.
I'm here to take your Mystic Eyes before the auction.
Appointed time?
The staff should've told you already...
that we'll be extracting your Mystic Eyes
half a day before the auction.
I see, so you thought this would be the perfect timing
for Rail Zeppelin to back up your deductions!
You are perceptive.
B-But wait!
Not yet!
Deputy Manager...
This is marvelous!
It falls short of Rainbow-class, but it'll likely reach at least Jewel-class.
Then, it really does?
A past shadow long gone can be brought back to the present like sea-foam.
Shall we name it "Mystic Eyes of Transience"?
I do apologize wholeheartedly for taking all of your precious time.
I hope you'll be able to resume a pleasant journey aboard Rail Zeppelin.
So, why are you tagging along?
Of course I'd tag along! I'm your best friend!
I'll cry if you keep being so cold to me! I'll cough blood!
Do you really think Mr. Karabo was the one who killed Miss Trisha?
There's a large difference between possibility and actual execution.
I'm terribly sorry. We're keeping you restrained for now.
Of course.
I'd like to ask you...
Were you really involved in a serial murder seven years ago?
I don't know.
I honestly had forgotten until just moments ago that I was involved in that incident.
The effects of your Mystic Eyes.
I can see the past.
It's forced on me even if I don't want to see.
Whether my eyes are open or shut,
the images flood in as if laughing at me that my eyelids don't matter.
However, at a greater pace than that, my own memories become shattered.
That's the kind of Mystic Eyes they were.
In other words, you were completely unable to control those Mystic Eyes.
I guess so.
But now, if I had those Mystic Eyes...
If I had them, I might finally be able to unravel the truth!
Then, you can buy the Mystic Eyes
back in the auction!
Perhaps, but it won't be a sum I can make a winning bid for.
I see. So, you just want to buy it back?
Melvin...
I can't guarantee it because I'm sure it'll be the most expensive item this time around.
But it might be fun to at least challenge myself.
Of course, it's only if it has that much amusement attached to it.
What do you think, Waver?
I have no intent on selling my soul to the devil.
A shame...
Isn't there something to make this case a bit more exciting?
By the way, when I met Miss Trisha...
Um...
Tucked in her clothes was, well, um...
something lewd.
What was that?
Tell me again! What did you see?
Um...
I saw a man and a woman connected together—
It's not strange to bring something in.
I myself had taken several defensive measures.
But nothing like that was at the crime scene.
Even if it was a defensive measure,
it's nowhere nearly as stable as a Mystic Eyes nullifier.
So, that means she had a different way to use it.
Master?
This is not a deduction.
I can't possibly call this a deduction.
However,
if what I imagine is true, I can say this...
The perpetrator is...
my enemy!
I will solve...
this case!