Trisha?
Trisha? Trisha? You're kidding me, right?
Why are you sleeping in a place like this?
Why won't you scold me like you usually do?
Miss Olga-Marie...
Her head is gone!
Contact the conductor!
There's no need for that.
Such a distressing turn of events.
Did you guys do this?
I-It must be you, Karabo!
It's you, isn't it?
Holy Church guys are magus killers!
Unfortunately not.
Would it be all right if I performed the autopsy?
I'm used to seeing corpses of this nature.
Give me a break!
Pardon me.
You. Take her.
S-Sure!
They quite readily allowed him to perform the autopsy.
Magi killing each other is a common occurrence aboard this train.
And the management won't concern themselves with each one.
Self-responsibility is fundamental.
Oh no.
Can I ask you one thing?
What is it?
You are a member of the Holy Church. Don't you find magi despicable?
Well, I feel all magi should have their souls burned in purgatory.
But that's a different matter from this.
The Black Keys bequeathed to me...
is not for piercing a young girl mourning the falling of a brethren.
It seems you really have strange ties to matters of this nature,
Lord El-Melloi II.
The same can be said for you.
I've been aboard the train the whole time.
Does that mean I have no alibi?
You know well that such concepts can't be applied to magi.
That's good.
We were aboard the train, as well.
I was outside with Karabo!
There were several other magi outside, so I'm sure I can get testimonies!
There is no doubt that the time of death is within one hour.
Cause of death is shock from beheading.
There are no traces of a scuffle,
so the perpetrator must've killed her in an instant.
But why did the perpetrator take her head?
She had the Mystic Eyes of Premonition.
I witnessed it myself.
Oh?
That means the perpetrator took her entire head
for the purpose of taking her Mystic Eyes.
Extracting Mystic Eyes from the head they took with them...
Is such a thing possible?
If it's aboard this Rail Zeppelin, that's a simple task.
In that case, I'd like to perform an autopsy myself.
Do you perhaps possess perception-type Mystic Eyes?
Why do you think that?
Considering your age, it's more natural to think
that the reason you're here is not to buy Mystic Eyes but to sell them.
Didn't you volunteer to do an autopsy
because you felt your Mystic Eyes were effective for that purpose?
Looks like I can't hide it from you, Lord.
My eyes are the Mystic Eyes of Past Vision.
He showed me its powers earlier, too.
It's not convenient enough to always be able to specify time and location, though.
Does that mean the initiative is with the Mystic Eyes and not with you?
Lately, my Mystic Eyes have been dragging me into visions more often.
I boarded this train to part ways with them.
Then, were you able to see the perpetrator?
No, I couldn't see that.
There might have been some kind of protection working.
I could see how she was sitting here in this chair,
but the conditions right around the beheading was vague, and I couldn't see clearly.
Then, the situation might've been vague for Trisha Fellows herself.
What?
If she'd noticed, she surely would've taken some measures.
At the least, she would have warned Olga-Marie as her subsidiary.
Which means her death and its perpetrator...
were not in either the Premonition or Past Vision.
He was invisible from both the past and the future.
It's as if it was a man invisible to time.
But you have no guarantee that I'm telling the truth to begin with.
Yes, but I'd like to put my faith in people like you.
I can't believe those are words of a Lord of the Clock Tower.
Mystic Eyes are not techniques but innate characteristics.
And if so, they should regulate how one lives, as well.
After all, humans are slaves to what they can see.
The world that we see can't be shared with anyone else.
I saw a friend become trapped within the dreams of Mystic Eyes the other day.
The fact that you see the past means that you can't live in the present.
I have not once lived in the moment.
Professor, Miss Olga-Marie has woken up.
Are you trying to make Animusphere owe El-Melloi a favor with something like this?
I have no such intent.
For me, this is something like a creed.
A creed?
Once, when I was still immature,
there was someone who said my immaturity was a sign of military might.
"Glory lies beyond the horizon."
I was struggling because I was seeking something beyond my reach.
And someday, willing or not,
I would discover my own path.
He kept telling me that.
If so, young ones yet to discover their paths unnecessarily losing their lives
is something I can't allow.
Were you told that during the Holy Grail War?
Perhaps by the Servant you summoned?
Yeah.
How ridiculous! A familiar influencing you? You're mistaking the means for the end!
That's not—
And yet humans still become slaves to what they see.
Gray, I'm trusting her with you.
I'll go negotiate with the conductor to prepare a new room for Lady Olga-Marie.
Let's go, Caules.
O-Okay!
He's weird.
Um, have some cocoa.
Hey, what is that weird Lord to you?
For me,
he's a very good mentor.
But...
you're not a magus, are you?
Even then, I'll be all right if I keep up with him.
That's how I feel.
Is that so?
Yes.
You're pretty weird yourself, following such a weird guy like him.
So I see.
Okay, understood.
Yep, Shishigou is over at the department head office in Slar.
Oh, he'll be all right.
What about the card I gave you?
Oh no, please don't hesitate to use it. After all, it will only increase your debt.
Jeez.
Such a troublesome elder brother.
What are you up to this time?
Oh, are you interested in Policies? Or myself?
Let's not play dumb.
You, the one who retrieved documents about this train from the Codrington Estate, are here.
I can't think you have no actual reason to be here.
Do you remember Gurdoa Davenant?
Yes, he was a pesky old man.
The one who sponsored Gurdoa,
and the one who sponsored Codrington...
It seems it was the same person.
Are you saying that person is involved with Rail Zeppelin?
I didn't go that far.
Besides, it's your job to deduce the answer, isn't it...
Mr. Detective?
There are no traces.
Same results with Spiritual Evocation.
Looks like the perpetrator did a good job of taking the relic out of here.
Maybe it didn't break past the bounded field.
What do you mean, Missie Hyena?
Wh-What's with that nickname?
Stealing spells is a specialty of the Edelfelt Family, right?
I won't deny that. From that viewpoint,
it seems the perpetrator had a spare key
for this bounded field to begin with.
So, it was an inside job after all.
Things are getting interesting.
It's almost the time that the perpetrator specified.
Escaping to the outside world is impossible, huh?
What do you mean?
This train is halfway to the underworld.
It would be very difficult to enter from the outside or escape from here.
So, that's what the invitations are for.
Correct. You can say that the invitations are keys to the underworld.
Therefore, if we create a gate using an invitation from this side,
we can use an adaptation of Touko Travel, and—
Um, Master...
Oh, sorry.
It's a bad habit for me to become so lost in something.
There are clouds now.
Is that...
Gray!
Something is approaching!
Master, over here!
Oh, you really did show up.
Should I mock someone for plunging in as a fool even if it's a trap?
Or should I praise him for having the fortitude capable of routing the enemy?
Are you the one who stole the relic from Master?
I am a vassal of the burglar.
Then give it back!
Gray!
Who...
are you?
I don't like your face.
Cheap, narrow-minded, gloomy and stubborn. A poor riser.
You look like you've seen the world,
but in the end, you're the one who disturbed things the most.
How was that? All of that applies to you, right?
They said Iskandar served under him, though temporarily,
so I wondered what kind of magus I'd see.
But this good-for-nothing?
I...
did not have him serve under me!
I was the King of Conqueror's subject!
A Subject? You?
We shared the same dream,
and I tried to keep pace with him.
And he commanded me to live!
So worthless.
I lured you out here simply because I had my curiosity prioritized.
However,
that ended up being in vain.
Oh, I've had enough!
I'm disgusted! There's only so much you can take before you're fed up!
So, die!
You are...
Remember! Simply having combat skills doesn't make you a warrior!
Becoming a warrior is an issue concerning everything!
Body, will and soul!
No way!
A Servant!
She's a Ghost Liner!
The materialization of a Heroic Spirit
engraved into human history!
Your mentor is a bit slow in giving you a warning!
That's an interesting stunt.
Did you absorb some of my magical energy?
This is rather fun.
I'll show you something good, then.
Mystic Eyes?
I believe you guys call it the "Noble Color of Coercion."
Isn't it a fitting end for this setting?
My god Dionysus values madness.
An image of mentor and apprentice killing one another seemed truly fit.
So, those glasses nullify Mystic Eyes.
Why you...
Hey, hey, Gray!
Serious? Are you serious? Hold on a second!
Oh, so you cleansed your magic circuit
with that scythe. Not bad.
I had hoped you'd be decent enough to settle your own score, but...
I won't let you!
No, it's already too late!
Bad, bad, bad! Gray, not that!
Anything but that!
What the...
That's...
It can't be!
Gordius Wheel?
Master,
is that...
It's Iskandar's Noble Phantasm!
My name is Hephaestion!
I am the primary confidante of the greatest King of Conquerors in history, Iskandar!
Master!
You have absolutely no qualifications to become one of Iskandar's subjects!
Gray. Rave.
You can't, Gray!
Using that at an unsecure foothold like this won't leave us unharmed!
Leave this to me.
Professor! Miss Gray!
Caules...
Are both of you okay?
She's not coming after us?
Unleashing something like that
means she'd be fighting the Mystic Eyes Collection Train itself.
I was a bit flustered.
I felt some magical energy in the lightning and came out to look
and saw that commotion.
But I'm so happy to see you, Caules.
Did you cut your hair?
I amplified a control spell with the magical energy stored in my hair
so that the thunder can flow down into the earth.
After all, hair symbolizes snakes, an incarnation of lightning.
Master, who in the world was that Servant?
She had toned things down.
If she really wanted to kill us,
such cheap tricks wouldn't be good enough.
No, in the first place,
how did she summon that thing?
Why is there...
a confidante to the king...
whom I've never seen before?
Master!
You said you can't leave people alone,
so why do you go off on your own and leave?
Please stand aside!
Hey!
That's a terrible burn!
I'll use the Primeval Battery!
I'll adjust the bioelectric currents
to heighten Professor's own healing powers.
I'll activate his Od as much as I can, too.
Will he be all right?
He'll be fine, right?
I'll do my best!
Hey, what's going on here?
Was he actually attacked by Trisha's murderer?
It's true that we were attacked.
But it has something to do with just us.
Master...
I'm disgusted!
If you're an apprentice to a magus,
you need to be prepared for something like this!
Well then, why don't you use this?
This is...
It's a Druid Elixir.
Druid Elixir?
Panacea, the cure-all?
Trisha handed it to me just in case,
but since I have no way to use it...
Thank you so much!
Look here.
With this, Animusphere no longer owes anything to El-Melloi!
That's all! Good night!
But to think, here I am, pretending to be detectives with a magician like you...
How I have fallen.
You say that, but you were acting rather lively.
It's not often you can rummage through the central core of Modern Magecraft Theory.
The previous department head has so many mysteries as is.
You mean Kayneth El-Melloi?
It wasn't him.
Is that so?
He was the Lord of Mineralogy.
You didn't even know that much?
The Clock Tower is a place that's difficult for me to approach.
So, who was the predecessor?
The predecessor wasn't a Lord to begin with—
Pardon me.
And so, my elder brother was seriously injured.
Yeah, consider your request itself to still be ongoing,
considering how Animusphere is making a move, as well.
Just get out of my way!
I only have need for one person, Reines El-Melloi Archisorte!
Sorry, I have to hang up now.
Lady, what is the meaning of this!
For starters, can you wipe up all the blood you've coughed up, Mister?
Oh, sorry.
Melvin Waynes...
My elder brother is not present, but I can take your message.
That's not what I'm here for!
Why didn't you tell me Waver had gotten aboard the Rail Zeppelin?
There was no need to tell you.
No, just by being his best friend,
I'm obligated to at least hear that much!
Unfortunately, I myself heard of the news several days ago.
And you didn't tag along, Reines?
Even though it seems so much fun?
As you can tell, I'm rather busy doing my job.
Then I have no choice but to go by myself.
Go by yourself?
Someone has to record Waver breaking into tears, so I'll go do it!
See this?
This is the financial powers of the Waynes Family.
As you'd expect from Panacea,
by combining it with the Primeval Battery,
we can accelerate cell activation.
With this...
Perhaps you should rest a bit?
There's no need to apply medicine on him anymore.
Thank you so much.
Caules, you're really calm.
Yeah. When my big sister said she was going to renounce being a magus,
I might've gained some courage.
Your big sister?
My big sister was what you'd call a genius.
But she suddenly renounced being a magus
and even gave up her magic crest
before leaving the family.
Of course, the entire family was in a riot from the top all the way down.
There even were guys who tried to kill someone ordinary like me
so she would resume being the head.
Sorry, that was a strange story, wasn't it?
It's okay. You'll become powerful.
More than your big sister, I'm sure.
Because Master picked you out!
God, I beg you.
Please don't give Master...
such a lonely way to die.