What happened to that case?
It was treated as trouble occurring between Dead Apostles.
No penalties for us nor for Policies.
I see.
So, you heard about my big sister?
Um, uh, well...
I'm sorry.
Oh no, it's fine!
I've told Flatt and the others long ago.
Is that so?
My big sister had a lot more talent than I do.
There are times when I think, "What if she had met Professor?"
But I like it here.
I'm glad I was able to come here,
and that I was able to meet everyone.
Me, too.
Everyone is waiting for you and Professor to return.
When Svin heard that you got injured, he had such a scary look on his face!
Scary look?
So maybe he does detest me.
Is Milady Gray all right? Milady Gray...
I want to suck in Milady Gray's sweet, beautiful and slightly melancholy scent now if I could!
That's why you get banned from her room, Le Chien!
Don't call me Le Chien! To begin with, because you—
If you're gonna make a scene, leave! Both of you!
Especially Svin! You should know your place!
I-I'm sorry, Professor!
Oh, that's right!
Here you go, Professor!
What is this?
What? It's a book you'd be delighted to see!
A book that guys just love!
That's right!
A strategy guide for a Dating Sim!
Professor, I heard you were a passionate researcher of Japanese games!
Let me assist you!
Whoa, looks like things are heating up!
I can't overlook this as a spy!
Weren't you being detained by Policies?
I made a plea bargain, so they released me!
Anyways,
someone real, compared to a game...
I don't care! All of you, get out!
Let me heal in peace!
Jeez.
If they didn't make such a ruckus, I would've been discharged a lot sooner.
Aren't they all just eager to have you back, Master?
It's all thanks to Father Karabo that we both made it back alive.
Yes.
He saved us until the very end.
But I was not able to save him.
Master...
Congratulations on your recovery.
I appreciate you coming out to say that.
The case from seven years ago will be closed after all.
I see.
The Holy Church didn't seem to want it brought back into the limelight after all this time.
There was one thing I wanted to ask you.
What is it?
You must surely be aware of the holes in your own deduction?
The reason why he summoned a Servant, is it?
It is true that Ghost Liners are precious resources.
I can understand how one would go so far to summon one.
If it's simply a matter of rarity, a Jewel-class Mystic Eyes will do.
Why does it have to be a Heroic Spirit?
What do you think about that?
I'm sure there is more to this case.
He said he'd be troubled if I died right now.
It's all about being necessities for the future.
Both myself and that Faker.
Yes.
In due time, I'll face that man once again.
I'm sure of it.
Overturn thyself!
I wanted to ask you a question, too.
Go ahead.
Trisha's pendant...
Why did you leave it behind?
I'm sure you have some sort of hypothesis about that, as well.
You said you were on that train on personal business.
Taking such drastic actions, confusing the crowd with a mistaken deduction...
Wasn't there someone you wanted to lure out?
Are you saying everything was what I'd intended?
So, it wasn't?
You're overestimating me.
Of course, the motive is as you've deduced.
After all, I did assist you, didn't I?
Yeah. Without your assistance,
I wouldn't have been able to restrain that fake Caules.
I saved your life.
In hindsight!
The answer to your question...
is something similar to you and Miss Reines.
Doctor Heartless is my elder brother-in-law.
Both of us were adopted children of Norwich.
I see.
By the way, I have one more question to ask.
Something else?
Why did you give up on bidding and drop out in the final phase?
If Reines took five more minutes to arrive, I...
Oh my.
Were you trusting Policies by chance?
Oh? Elder brother and Gray have just been discharged.
Do people say you unfortunately miss out on things?
It's not like I came here to see the two of them!
Pardon me, then.
I heard you helped out with treatment on my elder brother.
I couldn't afford Animusphere to owe a favor.
I see.
I do appreciate what he did about Trisha.
Lord El-Melloi spoke her words on her behalf.
If this was my elder brother, he'd say,
"Please add the suffix II."
Father...
would not even see me.
Oh?
If the Greater Grail met Father's...
Marisbury's expectations,
I'm sure his dream would've been realized.
But that is a time and a world unbeknownst to me.
I didn't expect you to be such the poet.
I like you.
In other words, you want a fair exchange of information, right?
We are both in line to succeed the title of Lord.
I don't think it's a bad thing to use this opportunity to deepen our relations.
You are quite different from that elder brother of yours.
Well, of course. We're not related by blood after all.
I see. I think I can be good friends with you.
Nice to be of acquaintance as long as we can be of utility for one another.
Mr. Melvin?
There was a special stockholders' meeting at mom's hotel.
It was a huge mess.
You seem to be busy.
Magi do have lives, after all.
So, um...
I tune the damaged main crest of the El-Melloi faction.
But separate from that, I'm also in possession...
of Waver's magic crest for the Velvet family.
Magic crest! The thing magi inherit from one generation to another!
Right.
What you could say is the biggest family heirloom.
Why do you have it, Mr. Melvin?
You know how Waver shouldered all of El-Melloi's debt from Lady Reines, right?
What he used as collateral for it was his magic crest.
If someone was holding it for him, I'd be the natural choice as a tuner, right?
So, Master...
took something that important to him...
It's the best collateral to collect in terms of not making a magus betray you!
I mean, it's synonymous as taking their purpose in life away from them.
Their purpose in life...
Um, I've been curious for a while.
Why do you call him "Waver," Mr. Melvin?
Because it'd be lonely if nobody called him Waver
when he relinquishes the title of Lord.
Lonely?
It may be true that the Holy Grail War
affected Waver greatly.
But...
the 19 years leading up to that must've been valuable for him, as well.
That, and the time after he stops being a Lord,
which will arrive at some point.
When he is no longer a Lord?
You look like you've never thought about it.
He's been changing until now, triggered by trivial things, hasn't he?
I'm sure he'll continue to do so.
For instance, something like the Fifth Holy Grail War.
And if that happens, he may perhaps depart from this place for good.
Even if that were to happen,
for me,
Master will still be Master.
He will be for everyone in the class, as well.
Yeah. I think that's fine in its own way.
Various people have varying sides to them.
It was fun to chat with you.
Well, I'll be going now.
Wandering child adrift in darkness,
step forward!
Answer with thy name establishing thee within this transient world.
My name is Svin Glascheit.
I seek to reach the Root using the wisdom of the beasts.
Thou art a child of the stars.
In this moment, thou art born of darkness and given life within the light.
On my name as Lord El-Melloi,
I grant thee, Svin Glascheit, the rank of Pride.
Another one of my students has surpassed me.
I'm confident in how to use my feet.
I've come this far all thanks to you, Professor.
Me and probably Flatt, too.
It's thanks to being taught by none other than you.
With this, we will conclude the ritual.
All witnesses, please greet with great applause our blessed child seeking the Root!
And yet another one of his students rise to the third rank of the Clock Tower.
Goodness gracious, your performance is a bit scary, Lord El-Melloi II.
Man, you really are amazing, Svin!
I'll never forget about you, genius!
Man, it's not like I'm graduating or anything.
You're just getting all set to fall from a child prodigy to a normal person at age 20!
You're not complimenting me at all, are you?
You're not thundering down on them like usual.
You're in a surprisingly good mood, elder brother.
Yeah.
I finally feel like a burden has been lifted from my shoulders.
I'm troubled if you sound like an old man
just because you have one more student with a Pride rank.
As my tutor, you need to—
That's right!
I must continue to get up close and intimate with who I am spying on!
You know...
He may perhaps depart from this place for good.
Master!
It can't be!
Perhaps, you're drinking a bit too much.
Lady, I may be a cheap drunk, but this much won't affect me.
In the first place, Reines was drinking ten times as much during that party earlier.
I feel Miss Reines holds her drink a bit too well.
It will affect your performance tomorrow!
The party was very lively.
Yeah. It's not often that you see someone rise to Pride while in their teens.
Just like my predecessor.
With that, my predecessor,
Kayneth El-Melloi Archibald, was established as a child prodigy.
And pushing all other factions aside, he reigned as a great Lord.
That was likely because everyone had to admit...
the scenery that he'd been seeing was ideal for magi.
It's a scenery that I couldn't share to the end. Not once.
I'm on the side of simply celebrating
and sending out my students as usual.
Um...
I have been saved thanks to you!
Because you've brought me out of that village!
I'm sure everyone appreciates you for all sorts of reasons.
So...
Svin told me the same thing earlier.
Perpetually a half-assed Lord incapable of doing anything like his great predecessor...
I still think that way about myself.
But if all of you guys tell me what you do,
maybe just a little bit...
Master,
will you be heading out after all?
About the Fifth Holy Grail War...
I officially...
stepped down from contention.
Why?
Participating in a Holy Grail War is settling matters for me personally.
It isn't settling matters for the Heroic Spirit Iskandar.
I have my regrets,
but it's nothing to be so fixated over.
As one of his subjects
and as a Lord of the Clock Tower,
the battlefield where I need to bring things to an end is not over there!
I'll dismantle the ploy he's trying to achieve by using Faker's,
in other words Iskandar's, power!
That, in fact, is what my duty is.
Master...
Gray, can you stand aside?
Sure!
I'm going to get some fresh air.
Um,
this...
I got it at the department store with Miss Reines and company...
Actually, I was thinking about giving this to you sooner!
I'm sorry!
I'm sure accepting something like this isn't...
Am I not always telling you, Lady?
The whydunit.
What is important...
is why you went through with it.
Gray,
I'm sorry, but I'm sure my powers won't be enough.
I want you to fight together with me.
If you are...
fine with me.
Thank you.
And I'm counting on you in the future.
Snow... It's early this year.
You know, Le Chien?
They say that when it snows in Japan, dogs run around on the bottom right of your screen.
I'm sure you're mixing two things in that statement.
This is new. You're not quipping with the usual "Don't call me a dog"?
Well, I was told to stay calm to suit my rank of Pride.
Oh, you've matured!
But that's not just me, is it?
Yeah. Everyone has learned from him.
Oh, it's Gray!
Where, where, where? Where's Milady?
And what happened to staying calm to suit your rank of Pride?
Yes.
Finally,
one of my students...
is headed that way.
You can assault him as much as you want now!
Why don't you go ahead and take his lips now or something?
What's wrong, boy?
You coming over here?
This is just a dream.
Merely an illusion that my brain and my memories have created.
What's this? You've gotten to wringing out words in some logical manner?
Of course.
It's what I lecture all the time.
But to think you'd be a teacher...
Complete with creases between your brows.
Even if the Holy Grail War is over, life continues...
to the point of absurdity.
Perhaps, I've changed a bit since then.
Maybe I haven't changed at all.
The one thing I can say, though,
is that I still can't stand alongside you yet!
Because the pain of the path leading there and the glory at its end
must be gained in real life.
Not here,
but in my...
in the battlefield of Lord El-Melloi II!
I see.
Then, I, as a transient dream, shall dare to ask this...
Has your journey so far been fun for you?
Yeah.
Of course...
Rider.
This is a journey...
to follow in your legacy!
We're starting class now!